<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Seabed2crest</title>
	<atom:link href="/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 09:11:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.7</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/seabed2crest-logo.png</url>
	<title>Seabed2crest</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>google maps</title>
		<link>/google-maps/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=google-maps</link>
					<comments>/google-maps/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[root]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 09:11:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=4948</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="gmap_canvas">
                <iframe
                  width="100%"
                  height="500"
                  id="gmap_canvas"
                  src="https://www.google.com/maps/embed?pb=!1m18!1m12!1m3!1d3884.9112707345357!2d77.56406965480224!3d13.16799423910376!2m3!1f0!2f0!3f0!3m2!1i1024!2i768!4f13.1!3m3!1m2!1s0x3bae19d7fe915333%3A0xcdb2c8559a5ac17!2sSeabed2Crest%20Technologies%20Private%20Limited!5e0!3m2!1sen!2sin!4v1707710141895!5m2!1sen!2sin"
                  frameborder="0"
                  scrolling="no"
                  marginheight="0"
                  marginwidth="0"
                ></iframe>
              </div><p>The post <a href="/google-maps/">google maps</a> first appeared on <a href="">Seabed2crest</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/google-maps/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hello world!</title>
		<link>/hello-world/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=hello-world</link>
					<comments>/hello-world/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[root]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 11:20:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to WordPress. This is your first post. Edit or delete it, then start writing!</p>
<p>The post <a href="/hello-world/">Hello world!</a> first appeared on <a href="">Seabed2crest</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to WordPress. This is your first post. Edit or delete it, then start writing!</p><p>The post <a href="/hello-world/">Hello world!</a> first appeared on <a href="">Seabed2crest</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/hello-world/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>15 Best AI Apps for Android to Make Life Easier</title>
		<link>/15-best-ai-apps-for-android-to-make-life-easier/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=15-best-ai-apps-for-android-to-make-life-easier</link>
					<comments>/15-best-ai-apps-for-android-to-make-life-easier/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[root]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 03:06:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AI & Data Science]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://live.21lab.co/kiraz/?p=49</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>As mobile devices increasingly develop and become an indispensable part of people’s daily lives, the demand for productive applications with the ability to improve efficiency and manage our busy schedules has risen exponentially. With the development of artificial intelligence (AI) technology, Android users can now access a wide range of applications that use machine learning algorithms to make [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/15-best-ai-apps-for-android-to-make-life-easier/">15 Best AI Apps for Android to Make Life Easier</a> first appeared on <a href="">Seabed2crest</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As mobile devices increasingly develop and become an indispensable part of people’s daily lives, the demand for productive applications with the ability to improve efficiency and manage our busy schedules has risen exponentially. With the development of artificial intelligence (AI) technology, Android users can now access a wide range of applications that use machine learning algorithms to make our lives easier and more streamlined.</p>



<p>Most people think of AI chatbots like ChatGPT when talking about artificial intelligence (AI). However, AI technology nowadays has come to the stage of explosion in every aspect of life, such as healthcare, education, design, etc. AI helps you work more scientifically. AI contributes to improving your health. AI simplifies photo editing for use in social activities. Join Orient Software to discover the 15 best free AI apps for Android and create a modernized and automated life in our latest piece.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="ai-adoption">AI Adoption &#8211; The Rise of AI Apps for Android</h2>



<p>The concept of artificial intelligence (AI) was first introduced in the 1950s. However, it was not until recently, when science and technology were increasingly developed, that AI technology really made a breakthrough and was adopted more into all areas of human life.</p>



<p>According to information from Forbes, around 4 in 5 companies deem AI to be a top priority in their business strategy. To keep up with the breath of technology, survive and create a competitive advantage in today’s business landscape, companies spearhead artificial intelligence through large-scale changing in their own technology products or operations.</p>



<p>As for mobile application development, as the number of mobile device users continues to grow, there is obviously a significant rise in AI-powered apps for Android devices. AI has given customers a completely different definition of user experience on enterprise Android apps. AI chatbots answer questions and consult customers quickly, 24/7. AI recognizes the account holder’s voice and allows users to use AI mobile apps hands-free. AI protects customer information by detecting threats of cyber-attacks.</p>



<p>Not only does AI bring benefits to individuals, but applying AI to Android apps also helps businesses get closer to the path of modernization and automation. AI has the ability to analyze customers’ behavior and usage habits of mobile apps and recommend necessary changes. AI automates routine business activities such as bill payments and meeting reminders.</p>



<p>All the above examples are a perfect testament to the new era of mobile applications, where the integration of AI is becoming a key factor in delivering exceptional user experiences.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="top-10-best-ai-apps">Top 15 Best Free Artificial Intelligence Apps for Android Devices</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading3-1">Google Assistant</h3>



<p>If you use Android phones, you’ve probably heard of Google Assistant at least once. Google Assistant is a voice-controlled virtual personal assistant developed by Google. As one of the Google AI-based Android applications, most smart devices currently come pre-installed with Google Assistant, so you don’t need to download it from the Google Play Store.</p>



<p>By using natural language technology and machine learning, this AI app for Android understands users’ voice commands and then provides relevant responses. Google Assistant even helps users make life easier by integrating other tools used for daily tasks like making appointments, playing music, setting reminders, and looking up information right on search engines, etc.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading3-2">Bing AI</h3>



<p>Microsoft Bing has long been known as a direct competitor to Google in the search engine market. According to Statista, if Google is currently the dominant search engine with a market share of up to 84%, Bing, in recent years, has put up an admirable fight with a nearly 9% market share in the PC space.</p>



<p>Bing’s expansion continues beyond this point. Recently, Microsoft Bing has incorporated ChatGPT &#8211; an AI chatbot developed by OpenAI into its search engine to provide users with more conversational and personalized search results. Bing, from a normal search engine, turned into a smart search engine called Bing AI/Ms. Bing with the help of artificial intelligence.</p>



<p>Similar to ChatGPT, Bing AI is a tool that integrates AI with the Bing browser to answer questions from users. A special feature of Bing AI is that it supports continuous updating of the latest data, while ChatGPT is limited to data until 2021. Bing AI tool helps users answer questions and create content quickly and is extremely convenient.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading3-3">Replika AI</h3>



<p>Replika AI is an AI chatbot and virtual app that uses AI tech and machine learning to provide you with a personalized and conversational experience. Unlike conventional AI chatbots that only give accurate answers based on user questions, the app is designed to serve as a companion for users, allowing them to talk about their thoughts and feelings in a safe and non-judgmental space.</p>



<p>By using natural language processing and deep learning algorithms, Replika AI is capable of understanding and responding to user queries in a human-like manner. The longer you talk, the better and more realistic the conversation between you and Replika AI will be. This AI application also includes other features, such as mood tracking and meditation exercises, helping users to improve their mental health and well-being.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading3-4">Lensa AI</h3>



<p>If you are a social media lover, you better not ignore Lensa AI &#8211; an all-in-one photo editing app that is powered by artificial intelligence. Launched in 2018 by Prisma Labs, Lensa AI is one of the popular AI applications for image and video post-editing available on both Android and IOS devices.</p>



<p>With Lensa AI capabilities, you can get flawless edits based on your real-life selfies in just one tap. This AI app offers users a wide range of features, including filters, effects, auto-enhancement, object recognition, and background removal. However, Lensa AI only really left a strong impression when it launched a feature called Magic Avatars in 2022. By allowing users to turn any image into unique images that almost look cartoon-like, Magic Avatars plays a role as a smart AI image generator and creates a new trend on social networks for a while.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading3-5">Google’s Socratic</h3>



<p>Socratic is a Google product developed to help users learn and solve curriculum and homework-related questions. Using Socratic is very simple. Students post any questions on this AI app. Socratic will use AI tech to recognize the problem and then provide a detailed explanation of the answer.</p>



<p>In addition, Socratic also contains a vast knowledge base of most subjects today, such as math, literature, physics, science, etc., supporting users to improve their overall knowledge and skills. These resources can be in the form of video tutorials, quizzes, or even practice problems.</p>



<p>Socratic has both a free version and a paid subscription. However, they have no functional difference. The only difference is that the paid subscription gives users a more seamless learning experience without having to be distracted by ads or other promotional content.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading3-6">ELSA Speak</h3>



<p>ELSA (English Language Speech Assistant) Speak is the right choice for individuals who want to improve their English-speaking skills. ELSA Speak uses advanced speech recognition and deep artificial intelligence to analyze the user’s voice and provide real-time feedback on their rhythm, pronunciation, and intonation.</p>



<p>Users only need to choose one of the lesson categories available on the app, and they will immediately be provided with a series of exercises and drills by the app to practice and hone their speaking skills. Whether you are a student, a professional, or someone who needs to improve their English language skills, ELSA Speak can help you achieve your goals early.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading3-7">Freeletics</h3>



<p>Freeletics is an AI fitness application for Android that helps busy users of all fitness levels to effectively access training programs and workout plans. Acting as a personal trainer, Freeletics provides you with 20 unique Training Journey of exercises and workouts, including cardio, strength training, and stretching. Every stage of the user’s training journey is analyzed by the AI-powered personal trainer to provide the optimal solution for each different fitness focus.</p>



<p>In addition to workout plans, Freeletics also acts as a nutritionist that provides users with meal schedules and recipes to support their fitness goals. The recipes and nutrition menu of this AI app includes a wide variety of dietary options, from vegetarian and vegan, to paleo diets.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading3-8">Wysa</h3>



<p>Wysa is a mental health care app using modern AI technology designed and developed by Touchkin eServices. Similar to a chatbot, Wysa uses a number of therapeutic techniques, such as cognitive behavioral therapy (CBT) and dialectical behavior therapy (DBT), to provide users with 150 different therapeutic techniques through chat conversations. Thereby managing, minimizing, and even eliminating user anxiety, stress, and depression.</p>



<p>For the free version, users can use Wysa’s standard tools, such as guided meditations, breathing exercises, and mindfulness practices. To have access to the entire library of tools and receive extra support from one-on-one sessions with a coach, you must subscribe to a premium version.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading3-9">Duolingo</h3>



<p>Want to learn a new language but don’t know where to start? Duolingo &#8211; a language learning app &#8211; is here to give users a fun and enjoyable language learning experience. Despite being a completely free educational platform, Duolingo offers users online courses in up to 40 different languages.</p>



<p>Instead of providing traditional courses, this app uses game-like elements, such as points, levels, badges, etc., to simplify language learning. After each successful level, Duolingo rewards users with scores for completing lessons and achieving milestones.</p>



<p>Duolingo courses are referenced and correspond to the Common European Framework of Reference (CEFR) &#8211; an international standard of language proficiency. In addition to language teaching, Duolingo also offers short assessments after learners complete a Unit in the course. Through this assessment, not only can learners review and test their knowledge, but Duolingo also has a basis for evaluating the effectiveness of its teaching and making necessary improvements.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading3-10">Microsoft Copilot</h3>



<p>Microsoft is expanding its ecosystem with new AI innovations. Following the success of Bing Chat &#8211; a conversational AI that is part of Microsoft’s Bing search engine, the company continues to mark its position by launching a new product called Microsoft Copilot.</p>



<p>Rather than a separate AI solution, Microsoft Copilot is an innovative AI feature integrated into Microsoft 365 applications like Word, Excel, PowerPoint, and Outlook. Users can simply ask questions, and Copilot will quickly find the most relevant answers to fulfill their commands. The tool is even capable of analyzing the context of the data being worked on, thereby providing the most relevant suggestions, summarizing information, and creating data visualizations based on distinct insights of each customer.</p>



<p>Using Copilot appropriately, in combination with the inherent usefulness of Microsoft Suite, you make complex tasks more accessible, reduce the cognitive load associated with digital work, thus increasing productivity and efficiency as a whole.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading3-11">Amazon Alexa</h3>



<p>Are you looking for a personal virtual assistant that is as powerful as Siri but operates on a platform other than iOS? Amazon Alexa is the answer.</p>



<p>Developed by Amazon, Amazon Alexa is an AI assistant that responds to voice commands. By giving Alexa voice commands, users can automate simple tasks from turning off lights and turning on security systems to playing music, setting alarms, and providing weather updates.</p>



<p>The tool is integrated and available on most Amazon Echo devices and even extends to third-party smart speakers, appliances, and other gadgets. Thanks to its broad smart home compatibility, Amazon Alexa is the top choice for home automation, helping people easily manage their living spaces and improve their quality of life to a new level.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading3-12">Gencraft</h3>



<p>AI algorithms are evolving at a dizzying pace in the current technology landscape. Once a tool for providing quick information, AI models now have the capability to transform words and images into unique art.</p>



<p>Gencraft is an AI art generator that is especially suitable for designers looking for creative inspiration and non-professional users who need to use simple images directly for personal purposes. With Gencraft, there is no barrier to user creativity. This smart application, in addition to providing numerous templates and tools to simplify the design process, also has the ability to create elaborate structures, compositions, and figures from text prompts.</p>



<p>Gencraft is compatible with both Android and iOS operating systems, making it easy to download to any mobile device and use it anywhere with just an Internet connection.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading3-13">Cleo</h3>



<p>Having a headache over monthly expenses? Cleo is here to help.</p>



<p>As an AI-powered financial assistant for all users, Cleo is here to make managing your finances more efficient than ever. It can link directly to users’ bank accounts and act as an experienced money coach. Using AI and natural language generation, Cleo offers a wide range of features to help you manage a personal budget through valuable personalized insights into spending and bills, improving your financial habits in the long run.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading3-14">AI Mirror</h3>



<p>AI Mirror is a photo editing application with integrated AI technology designed for image transformation purposes. From an existing photo in your mobile device, for example, AI Mirror allows users to turn it into an artistic masterpiece with just a few simple steps. A diverse collection of image styles, filters, and animation themes is one of the most important supporting features that help you complete your own unique artwork.</p>



<p>Rather than creating an entirely new image from scratch, AI Mirror enhances users’ images with AI-driven artistry and is especially suitable for tech-savvy individuals who need to diversify content on popular social media platforms like Instagram, Discord, etc.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading3-15">Google Lens</h3>



<p>The list of free AI apps for Android ended with Google Lens. Developed by Google, Google Lens is a visual search engine that uses machine learning and computer vision technologies to analyze and understand images and objects in the real world. Based on the characteristics of the elements on the image you provide, Google Lens gives the closest search results about the origin, definition, and information related to the subject of the original image.</p>



<p>What is more, Google Lens also has the ability to coordinate with other Google applications, such as Google Assistant and Google Photos, to handle work. For example, by pointing the camera towards the row of SSID labels on the back of the router, users can easily connect to Wi-Fi automatically. This process is divided into two stages. In it, Google Lens will be responsible for information processing, and Google Assistant will be responsible for activating Wi-Fi.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading2-3">Final Note</h2>



<p>Above is a list of 15 interesting apps for Android for you. The intelligence of AI is undeniably growing. We can expect to see even more innovative and sophisticated AI-powered mobile apps in the future. However, the human brain is still superior to AI. So, instead of completely depending on the above applications, it is advisable to use them as effective tools to serve the needs of life.</p>



<p>Though on-the-shelf AI products are undeniably superior, the fact is that they cannot cater to your 100% pain points and unique business requirements. If you are still looking for an AI solution tailored to your specific needs, self-developing one is the best solution. With Artificial Intelligence services since 2005, Orient Software has cooperated with several clients across the globe and successfully transformed hundreds of AI concepts into reality. Feel free to reach out to us for a complimentary quote or expert advice.</p><p>The post <a href="/15-best-ai-apps-for-android-to-make-life-easier/">15 Best AI Apps for Android to Make Life Easier</a> first appeared on <a href="">Seabed2crest</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/15-best-ai-apps-for-android-to-make-life-easier/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Much Does Hiring App Developers Cost?</title>
		<link>/how-much-does-hiring-app-developers-cost/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=how-much-does-hiring-app-developers-cost</link>
					<comments>/how-much-does-hiring-app-developers-cost/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[root]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 03:02:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Outsourcing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://live.21lab.co/kiraz/?p=47</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The app economy is flourishing, with millions of apps vying for user attention. In order to stand out, businesses are investing heavily in mobile app development. Mobile apps have become indispensable support tools for companies aiming to enhance customer engagement and streamline operations. But how much does it actually cost to hire app developers? The answer [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/how-much-does-hiring-app-developers-cost/">How Much Does Hiring App Developers Cost?</a> first appeared on <a href="">Seabed2crest</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The app economy is flourishing, with millions of apps vying for user attention. In order to stand out, businesses are investing heavily in mobile app development. Mobile apps have become indispensable support tools for companies aiming to enhance customer engagement and streamline operations. But how much does it actually cost to hire app developers? The answer isn’t straightforward, as it depends on various factors such as app complexity, developer location, and the chosen platform.</p>



<p>For instance, the hourly rates for app development in the US typically hover around $100 per hour. A basic app with essential features can cost between $5,000 and $50,000, while a medium-complexity app might range from $50,000 to $120,000. Interestingly, the global in-app spending has surged threefold since 2016, reaching a staggering $170 billion by 2023.</p>



<p>Understanding these costs and the factors influencing them is vital for businesses planning to invest in app development. Dive into our comprehensive guide to get a clearer picture of what to expect when hiring app developers and how to make the most of your investment.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading2-1">Cost of Hiring Mobile App Developers from Different Service Types</h2>



<p>The cost of hiring a mobile app developer varies significantly depending on the service type you choose: freelance developers, development agencies, or in-house development teams.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Freelance Mobile App Developers</h3>



<p>When you hire an app developer on a freelance basis, you typically engage with professionals who work independently or as part of a small team. These developers offer a diverse range of skills and experiences, often having worked on various projects across different industries. This diversity can be beneficial as it enables innovative approaches and solutions tailored to specific project needs.</p>



<p>Freelance mobile app developers are often a cost-effective option for many businesses, especially startups and small enterprises. The cost of hiring freelance developers can vary widely based on their experience, location, and the complexity of the project. Freelancers typically charge on an hourly basis, with rates ranging from $20 to $150 per hour. For a simple app, the total cost might be between $5,000 and $50,000, while more complex apps can cost upwards of $100,000.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">App Development Agencies</h3>



<p>Partnering with app development agencies offers several distinct advantages. These agencies typically have a dedicated app development team that includes designers, developers, project managers, and quality assurance specialists. This comprehensive team approach ensures that all aspects of the app development process are handled professionally and efficiently. App development companies often have established processes and methodologies, which can turn your app idea to higher quality outcomes and more predictable project timelines.</p>



<p>The cost of hiring an app development agency is generally higher than hiring freelancers due to the added value of a full-service team and established processes. Agency rates can range from $50 to $200 per hour. The total cost for developing a simple app with an agency might range from $20,000 to $100,000, while complex apps can exceed $200,000.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">In-House Developers</h3>



<p>Hiring in-house developers involves bringing developers onto your payroll as full-time employees. This option provides the most control over the development process but also comes with higher costs due to salaries, benefits, and other employment-related expenses. The annual salary for an in-house mobile app developer can range from $70,000 to $150,000, depending on their experience and location. Additionally, the total cost of developing an app in-house includes not only salaries but also the costs of recruitment, training, and maintaining development infrastructure.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-table"><table class="has-fixed-layout"><thead><tr><th>Service Type</th><th>Hourly Rate Range</th><th>Total Cost for Simple Apps</th><th>Total Cost for Complex Apps</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>Freelance Developers</td><td>$20 &#8211; $150</td><td>$5,000 &#8211; $50,000</td><td>$50,000 &#8211; $100,000+</td></tr><tr><td>App Development Agencies</td><td>$50 &#8211; $200</td><td>$20,000 &#8211; $100,000</td><td>$100,000 &#8211; $200,000+</td></tr><tr><td>In-House Developers (Annual)</td><td>$70,000 &#8211; $150,000</td><td>Varies based on salaries</td><td>Varies based on salaries</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading2-2">Cost Estimation Methods</h2>



<p>Understanding the different ways app development costs are calculated is essential for budgeting and planning your project. As we’ve discussed, factors like the service provider significantly influence the overall cost. Let’s delve deeper into the two primary cost estimation methods: hourly rates and fixed project pricing.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Hourly Rates</h3>



<p>Hourly rates are a common method for estimating the cost of mobile app development. This approach involves charging customers based on the number of hours spent on the project. It offers flexibility, allowing for adjustments in the project scope and requirements as development progresses. Hourly billing is particularly beneficial for projects with uncertain or evolving requirements, as it allows for ongoing adjustments without the need for renegotiation.</p>



<p>The hourly rates to hire mobile app developers can vary significantly depending on their experience and geographic location. For instance, junior developers with less experience might charge between $20 and $50 per hour, while mid-level developers typically charge between $50 and $100 per hour. Senior developers or specialists with extensive experience can command rates ranging from $100 to $150 per hour or more.</p>



<p>Geographic location is also a crucial factor in determining hourly rates. Developers based in Western Europe and North America generally have higher rates, often between $100 and $200 per hour, due to the demand for skilled professionals and higher cost of living in these regions. In contrast, developers in Eastern Europe, Asia, and Latin America may charge lower rates, typically ranging from $20 to $75 per hour, making them an attractive option for cost-conscious clients.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Fixed Project Pricing</h3>



<p>Fixed project pricing is another popular cost estimation method where the total cost of the project is agreed upon upfront, based on a detailed project scope and requirements. This model offers clients a clear understanding of the total investment required, reducing the risk of budget overruns. Fixed project pricing is ideal for projects with well-defined requirements and minimal expected changes. It ensures that both the client and the developer have a mutual understanding of the deliverables, timelines, and costs involved.</p>



<p>Several factors influence the total cost of fixed-price app development projects. The app’s complexity is a primary determinant; simple apps with basic features and functionalities typically cost between $10,000 and $50,000. More complex apps with advanced features, integrations, and customizations can range from $50,000 to $200,000 or more.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Negotiation Tips</h3>



<p>Regardless of the cost estimation method, clients can employ various negotiation strategies to optimize the overall cost of app development. Some key tips include:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list list-style1">
<li><strong>Negotiate hourly rates or fixed project pricing:</strong> Clients should research the market rates and compare quotes from different vendors to ensure they are getting a fair and competitive price.</li>



<li><strong>Explore options for phased development:</strong> Breaking the project into smaller, manageable phases can help reduce the initial investment and allow for more flexibility in the development process.</li>



<li><strong>Discuss potential cost-saving measures:</strong> Clients can work with the app development provider to identify areas where costs can be optimized, such as using open-source frameworks, leveraging existing code libraries, or exploring more efficient development approaches.</li>



<li><strong>Negotiate payment terms and milestones:</strong> Clients can negotiate the payment schedule, such as upfront deposits, progress payments, or final payments upon project completion, to better manage their cash flow.</li>



<li><strong>Seek long-term partnerships:</strong> Clients who are willing to commit to a long-term relationship with an app development provider may be able to negotiate more favorable pricing and better access to the provider’s resources and expertise.</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading2-3">Additional Cost Considerations</h2>



<p>Beyond the core development costs, several other factors can significantly impact the overall budget for your app project.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Platform Selection</h3>



<p>The choice of platform also plays a crucial role in determining app development costs. Developers must decide whether to create for iOS, Android, or both and whether to use native or cross-platform development.</p>



<p>Developing an app for a single platform, such as an iOS app for the Apple App Store or an Android app, typically costs less than developing for both platforms. Native mobile app development for each platform requires different programming languages (Swift for iOS and Kotlin or Java for Android), which can increase costs if both platforms are targeted. Cross-platform development, using frameworks like React Native or Flutter, can reduce costs by allowing code reuse across platforms but may still require platform-specific adjustments.</p>



<p>There are certain criteria and design rules for each platform. For instance, iOS apps must adhere to Apple’s Human Interface Guidelines, while Android apps follow Material Design principles. These platform-specific requirements can influence the app development process, as developers need to ensure compliance with each platform’s standards. Additionally, the software development process may involve different testing and optimization procedures for each platform, further impacting costs.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Maintenance and Support Costs</h3>



<p>Maintenance and support are ongoing costs that can significantly impact your budget over time. Security patches, regular updates, and technical support are necessary to ensure the smooth operation of your platform. For example, hiring a full-time IT professional for maintenance can cost between $50,000 and $80,000 annually. Alternatively, outsourcing these services to a managed service provider might cost between $100 and $200 per hour. Additionally, consider the cost of software licenses, which can range from a few hundred to several thousand dollars annually, depending on the software’s complexity and the number of users. It’s also important to factor in the potential costs of downtime, which can be substantial. For instance, Gartner estimates that the average cost of IT downtime is $5,600 per minute, highlighting the importance of reliable support and maintenance.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading2-4">Summarize</h2>



<p>When it comes to developing a mobile app, the cost of hiring app developers is a crucial consideration. As outlined in this article, there are several approaches to estimating app development costs, including hourly rates, fixed project pricing, and various negotiation strategies.</p>



<p>Freelance app developers can offer a more cost-effective solution, with hourly rates ranging from $20 to $150. However, working with a team of experienced professionals at an app development agency may provide more comprehensive support, with hourly rates typically between $50 and $200.</p>



<p>For clients seeking a more predictable budget, fixed project pricing can be an attractive option, with costs ranging from $10,000 to $100,000 or more, depending on the app’s complexity and the scope of the project.</p>



<p>Regardless of the approach, it’s essential for clients to thoroughly research the market, compare quotes, and negotiate effectively to ensure they get the best value for their investment. Exploring options like phased development, cost-saving measures, and long-term partnerships can further optimize the overall cost of app development.</p>



<p>If you’re considering hiring app developers, we encourage you to explore the services offered by Orient Software. As an experienced outsourcing provider, we can offer a talented team of app developers, designers, and project managers at competitive rates. By partnering with Orient Software, you can benefit from their expertise, streamlined processes, and dedication to delivering high-quality mobile app solutions that meet your business needs.</p>



<p>Take the next step in bringing your app idea to life by contacting Orient Software today. Our team is ready to work with you to create a customized app development plan that fits your budget and timeline.</p><p>The post <a href="/how-much-does-hiring-app-developers-cost/">How Much Does Hiring App Developers Cost?</a> first appeared on <a href="">Seabed2crest</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/how-much-does-hiring-app-developers-cost/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Java Integration Testing Explained With Examples</title>
		<link>/java-integration-testing-explained-with-examples/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=java-integration-testing-explained-with-examples</link>
					<comments>/java-integration-testing-explained-with-examples/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[root]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 02:57:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Quality Assurance]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://live.21lab.co/kiraz/?p=45</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In software development, testing is the basic yet fundamental stage in the entire lifecycle that ensures the quality of the final deliverable. There are actually numerous types of testing methods: Functional testing, load testing, performance testing, automated testing, system testing, end-to-end testing, sanity testing, and smoke testing, acceptance testing, to name a few. Among test methods, integration testing is a vital aspect [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/java-integration-testing-explained-with-examples/">Java Integration Testing Explained With Examples</a> first appeared on <a href="">Seabed2crest</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In software development, testing is the basic yet fundamental stage in the entire lifecycle that ensures the quality of the final deliverable. There are actually numerous types of testing methods: Functional testing, load testing, performance testing, automated testing, system testing, end-to-end testing, sanity testing, and smoke testing, acceptance testing, to name a few.</p>



<p>Among test methods, integration testing is a vital aspect of any development cycle, typically Java development. Long story short, Java is one of the most popular programming languages of all time, and it is often trusted for the development of web and mobile applications, games, and many other enterprise-scale software thanks to its advantages.</p>



<p>So, what’s the main topic here? In this overview, we are going to clarify the concept of Java integration testing and what it entails. Let’s roll.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What Is Integration Testing?</h2>



<p>First and foremost, integration testing is a phase in the software testing process wherein all the software modules, units, or individual components are gathered and verified as a unified group. Unlike in unit testing, specific components or modules are validated in isolation. In a unit test, only a single unit or code snippet is assessed.</p>



<p>In an integration test, the primary goal is to evaluate the interactions and test data exchange between different separate parts of the software. Through the test results, discrepancies, bugs, or code conflicts that surface when units work together as a whole are revealed. An integration test fails if a part of the software system is faulty or unavailable, and the other components depend on it. Such failures are called integration errors.</p>



<p>Hence, integration testing is meant to prevent any risk of integration errors that could impact the functionality, performance, or user experience of the application. In case defects are found, users should perform positive and negative integration testing simultaneously. Positive testing includes normal inputs that ought to generate expected outputs, while negative one is used to examine invalid or erroneous inputs that are likely to produce incorrect outcomes.</p>



<p>In today’s complicated software ecosystems, the definition and scope of integration testing have expanded. Therefore, modern applications often depend on external systems, services, and APIs (Such as third-party payment gateways, data feeds, cloud services, etc.). It is essential to test not just the internal integrations but also how a system reacts to the external resources.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What Is a Java Integration Test?</h2>



<p>Java integration testing adheres to the same principles yet focuses on Java-specific frameworks, technologies, libraries, and tools. Additionally, Java integration tests are often performed in conjunction with unit testing to guarantee the full coverage of the codebase.</p>



<p>Usually, testers perform integration testing after unit tests are executed and before system testing. If a unit test fails, a fix is required, and the entire integration test suite is rerun to ensure that the changes did not break any other components. A failed unit test may potentially lead to a failed integration test, but the reverse is not always true.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Approaches to Java Integration Tests</h2>



<p>Integration tests can be conducted using various approaches comprising top-down, bottom-up, big bang, or sandwich testing. Each comes with its methodology for combining and testing the integrated components.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Big Bang Integration Testing</h3>



<p>The Big Bang is an all-or-nothing strategy where all the components are integrated and tested at once. This approach is straightforward, so it is much time-saving yet risky, as identifying the root cause of a failure can be challenging due to the large number of interacting components.</p>



<p>Moreover, it is prone to missing out on integration errors as you are testing all the modules at the same time or when the project complexity escalates. Thus, Big Bang testing is more convenient for small systems with fewer modules.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Incremental Integration Testing</h3>



<p>In contrast with the Big Bang, the incremental approach involves executing integration tests of crucial modules or components of a system one by one. Under this approach, there are two sub-strategies:</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Top-down</h3>



<p>In a hierarchical manner, it starts from the top-level critical modules of a software system and gradually down to the lower-level ones. High-level modules are tested first.</p>



<p>During the process, stubs (dummy modules) or simulated versions (mocks) that provide the expected behavior of the lower-level modules (which have yet to be integrated) may be used. It is advantageous to detect issues at the topmost, but it is also a drawback as you have to wait for the development of the critical modules.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Bottom-up</h3>



<p>Likewise, the bottom-up approach begins with the integration and testing of lower-level modules first before moving upwards. Drivers, or temporary modules, are used to simulate higher-level modules that have not yet been integrated.</p>



<p>This test method enables early testing, as you can begin writing tests as soon as the modules are built. Unfortunately, critical errors may be detected late in the development cycle, making it harder to trace and fix.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Sandwich Integration Testing</h3>



<p>This is a mixed approach in which bottom-up and top-down integration testing methods are combined, which provides a balance between the two approaches. Sandwich testing makes it viable for the simultaneous integration testing of both ends (The top and bottom levels) while the intermediate levels are tested incrementally.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Common Java Integration Testing Frameworks</h2>



<p>Java supports a vast range of libraries and frameworks for testing purposes. Therefore, choosing the right Java integration testing framework is necessary. Here, let’s outline a few popular options:</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Spring Boot Test</h3>



<p>The first widely used integration testing framework is Spring Boot Test. This one creates a test environment for applications built on Spring.</p>



<p>Spring Boot Test is capable of running integration tests in a real or simulated production environment. It utilizes the spring-test module and JUnit to execute tests, which facilitates dependency injection and test context configuration. Also, it provides robust support for web server testing and external service mocking.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">JUnit</h3>



<p>It is an open-source test framework created for the purpose of writing, running, and documenting test cases in Java programming logic. JUnit is a popular framework choice within the Java ecosystem, and it is primarily used to perform unit tests.</p>



<p>However, JUnit does support other types of testing, including integration testing. Its role has been instrumental in promoting the practice of test-driven development (TDD) among Java developers. At present, the latest version of JUnit is JUnit5, which introduces a more modular and flexible architecture than its predecessors, offering fresh features to enhance testing practices for modern Java software.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Selenium</h3>



<p>Selenium is also an open-source framework built for testing web applications. It is compatible with many different programming languages, such as Java, C#, Python, Ruby, and JavaScript. This makes Selenium a versatile choice for a broad range of development environments.</p>



<p>Selenium supports various types of testing. When it comes to integration testing, Selenium’s strengths are evident in its ability to simulate real-world user interactions with web applications. In Java development, Selenium is often combined with other testing frameworks, like JUnit or TestNG, to conduct integration tests.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">TestNG</h3>



<p>The “NG” in TestNG stands for “Next Generation.” Created by Cedric Beust, TestNG was inspired by JUnit and NUnit but introduced some new functionalities that made it more powerful and easier to use, particularly for larger test suites and integration testing.</p>



<p>It is an advanced testing framework for Java programming. In addition to integration testing, TestNG covers other categories of testing, namely unit and functional tests.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Mockito</h3>



<p>Mockito is renowned as a handy and flexible framework for its mocking capabilities &#8211; which enables developers to mock dependencies of the units they need to test.</p>



<p>In the case of integration tests, Mockito can be combined with other testing frameworks, such as TestNG or JUnit, to simulate the dependencies of the system under test. Mockito is simple and straightforward to use. It follows a strict syntax, which reduces ambiguity while writing tests. On top of its basic mocking capabilities, Mockito also brings forth advanced features like spies and verification modes.</p>



<p>Other integration testing frameworks for Java include:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list list-style1">
<li>Cucumber is focused on behavior-driven development (BDD),</li>



<li>Arquillian is great for testing Java EE components in a container,</li>



<li>Citrus excels in testing message-based applications and data formats,</li>



<li>Rest Assured specializes in testing RESTful web services.</li>
</ul>



<p>It is worth noting that a number of factors determine the suitability of a framework for integration testing, such as project requirements, available resources, and technical expertise. So, don’t choose a framework that people proclaim to be the best; find one that fits your specific context and testing requirements instead.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Best Practices for Java Integration Testing</h2>



<p>As with any other test methods, there are certain practices that should be strictly followed when you run integration tests in Java code. They include:</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Start Early &amp; Test in Small Batches</h3>



<p>This is the basic rule of thumb. Integration testing helps developers uncover potential issues at an early stage of software development, which means a unit should be tested as soon as it is built. It would be ideal to run tests after each code change or at least on a regular basis.</p>



<p>Moreover, integration testing should be carried out in small batches so that developers can detect issues and rectify them quickly, especially since the scope is limited. Accomplish these two assignments, and you can avoid last-minute surprises.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Create Test Environments Similar to the Production</h3>



<p>For integration testing, the test environment must resemble the production one as closely as possible while securing control over external dependencies and services that may impact the test outcomes.</p>



<p>How? Make certain that you include all necessary configurations and dependencies that reflect the production environment in your test environment. Only in such a condition can the tests be done in a relevant and realistic context, resulting in more accurate results.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Use Detailed Logging Statements</h3>



<p>When a Java integration test fails, debugging becomes a cumbersome task, pronto. Therefore, it is vital to log every step of the testing process. In an efficient manner, detailed logging helps you trace the points of failure down to the execution of each test case. By examining logs of code sections, you can pinpoint the exact bottlenecks and where to make improvements or fixes.</p>



<p>The usage of detailed logging statements can be further strengthened with the aid of log analysis tools, which will help to sift through a vast amount of log data more efficiently.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Design Independent, Executable Test Cases</h3>



<p>You should be mindful of the test case strategy. Your integration test should be designed to run independently and with the least dependencies. In this way, you can ensure test case isolation, which helps validate the individual functionalities thoroughly without any interference from external resources.</p>



<p>Furthermore, your tests should be made easily executable for other team members who might not possess the same technical expertise as the one who wrote the tests. A little tip: Use clear naming conventions for test cases and keep them well organized in suites for easy maintenance and execution.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Separate Java Unit Testing &amp; Integration Testing</h3>



<p>Developers should not utilize unit testing and integration testing concurrently. Why should we avoid it? Unit testing is directed at checking the isolated, smaller components of the code, while integration testing evaluates their behaviors when they interact with each other. As they fulfill different purposes, mixing them can cause confusion or lead to flawed results.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Automate Testing Processes</h3>



<p>Automation is essential for different stages of software development, including testing.</p>



<p>Automated integration testing helps speed up the process of validating software functionality and reduces the scope for human errors. Automation also enables developers to run tests more frequently and consistently, and it allows them to address problems promptly.</p>



<p>Developers can leverage a variety of tools or frameworks to automate most of the manual processes in order to save time and effort while boosting testing quality. In addition, the continuous integration/continuous deployment (CI/CD) pipeline is another valuable tool for automating testing processes and ensuring that all tests are run in a systematic, timely manner.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Software Testing Services Empowered by Orient Software</h2>



<p>Come to Orient Software if you are asking for software testing services or personnel. Briefly introducing, Orient Software is a software outsourcing house that has spent almost two decades in the IT outsourcing industry. Rest easy because we have been handling and delivering a plethora of projects like yours before.</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list list-style1">
<li><strong>QA Testing Services:</strong> Our team consists of experienced testers and QA engineers who have excellent skills and relevant experience in quality assurance and testing. We cover a versatile range of software testing methods, including the ones you need.</li>



<li><strong>Dedicated Teams or Augmented Staff:</strong> Scale your in-house testing team with our resources, all while maintaining budget control and delivery speed as well as quality. Or, if you require a full-fledged team, we can also provide that upon your request.</li>
</ul>



<p>Alongside software testing services, Orient Software specializes in custom software development services as well. Your project will be in our good hands, so contact us today if you need a reliable, competent partner for your IT needs</p><p>The post <a href="/java-integration-testing-explained-with-examples/">Java Integration Testing Explained With Examples</a> first appeared on <a href="">Seabed2crest</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/java-integration-testing-explained-with-examples/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Top 10 Promising 5G Business Opportunities</title>
		<link>/top-10-promising-5g-business-opportunities/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=top-10-promising-5g-business-opportunities</link>
					<comments>/top-10-promising-5g-business-opportunities/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[root]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 02:38:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Business Innovation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://live.21lab.co/kiraz/?p=42</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>5G has been quite the buzzword for some time. When comparing it to its predecessors, like 4G, its theoretical download speeds are ten faster. Its latency (the time it requires for data to travel from its source to the destination) is less than one millisecond. 4G’s latency is less than ten milliseconds. The latest mobile [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/top-10-promising-5g-business-opportunities/">Top 10 Promising 5G Business Opportunities</a> first appeared on <a href="">Seabed2crest</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>5G has been quite the buzzword for some time. When comparing it to its predecessors, like 4G, its theoretical download speeds are ten faster. Its latency (the time it requires for data to travel from its source to the destination) is less than one millisecond. 4G’s latency is less than ten milliseconds.</p>



<p>The latest mobile versions, like the iPhone 15 and Samsung Galaxy S24, support 5G, and it is gradually becoming the new standard for mobile devices.</p>



<p>Do faster data speeds and new standards mean better services? What implications and impacts does 5G have on business opportunities? By examining 5G, the technology’s current state of infrastructure and the roles of stakeholders will provide us with an insight into these questions.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Key Takeaways:</h3>



<ul class="wp-block-list list-style1">
<li>5G is a new-generation technology that facilitates strong and reliable connections, low latency, and increased bandwidth.</li>



<li>5G-enhanced technology paves the way for multiple business opportunities, including smart IoT technologies, seamless remote work and remote healthcare services, data-driven business decisions, accelerating digital transformation, and more.</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading2-1">An Overview of 5G Technology &#8211; What is it and How it Works</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Definition</h3>



<p>5G stands for fifth-generation mobile technology. It is the new standard for telecommunications networks. While it uses the same frequencies as 3G and 4G, it provides quicker download rates, reduced latency, and increased bandwidth, which means improved dependability, stronger connectivity, and shorter download times.</p>



<p>In addition, 5G facilitates seamless roaming between cellular and Wi-Fi networks without the need for reauthentication, improving digital activities like online gaming and videoconferencing. Its dense, distributed-access architecture brings data processing closer to users, enabling faster processing.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">How Does 5G Work?</h3>



<p>Similar to communication systems, 5G technology uses radio frequency to transmit information through air. However, it does so with a less cluttered and higher frequency.</p>



<p>High bandwidth allows 5G to carry data faster, but it also faces the challenges of traveling over long distances, which are often obstructed by buildings or trees. Numerous input and output antennae are used to boost the signal and capacity of wireless networks to solve this problem. Smaller transmitters are also placed on buildings and street furniture.</p>



<p>Another notable capability of new-generation cellular technology is its ability to “slice” physical networks. Physical network slicing enables the creation of multiple virtual networks on top of the shared network. This allows operators to “slice” the network based on the user’s demand. For example, a video streamer’s network demands are different from that of a student or a business. This agility also allows enhanced mobile broadband or enterprises to purchase their own private networks.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading2-2">A Quick Look at 5G Adoption Statistics</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Global Statistics</h3>



<ul class="wp-block-list list-style1">
<li>From 2019 to 2028, there will be a sharp rise in 5G subscribers globally, from over 12 million to over 4.5 billion, according to projections. According to region, the highest subscription rates are anticipated in North East Asia, Southeast Asia, India, Nepal, and Bhutan. (Statista)</li>



<li>Berg Insight’s research report shows 2,900 private LTE/5G networks globally deployed by 2023, with 700 networks transitioning from trials to commercial operations. The number is expected to grow at a 33% CAGR until 2028, reaching 11,900 networks. Many networks will be upgraded to 5G within the next 2-3 years.</li>



<li>By the end of 2023, around 45% of the world’s population is going to have access to 5G, and by 2029, that percentage is anticipated to rise to 85%. (Ericsson)</li>
</ul>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Vietnam Statistics</h3>



<ul class="wp-block-list list-style1">
<li>Vietnam aims to commercialize 5G nationwide in 2024. (Tuoitrenews)</li>



<li>The Government News reported that the National Institute of Information and Communications Strategy estimates, that 5G services will increase Vietnam’s GDP by about 7.34 percent by 2025.</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading2-3">The Roles of Business and Stakeholders in Transformations with 5G</h2>



<p>To truly make use of 5G business opportunities, you need to be aware of the stakeholders and their roles.</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list list-style1">
<li><strong>Network Service Providers (NSPs)</strong> develop, offer, and maintain control over infrastructure and service quality.</li>



<li><strong>Communication Service Providers (CSPs)</strong> are the ones to provide services to Online Service Providers (OSPs) and end-customers.</li>



<li><strong>Online Service Providers (OSPs)</strong>, in addition to collaborating with NSPs for secured services, deliver and represent vertical industry stakeholders (E.g., automotive, energy, health) and provide tailored products to end-users.</li>



<li><strong>Device manufacturers and network infrastructure manufacturers</strong> offer proper devices and infrastructure for network deployment.</li>



<li><strong>End-customers</strong> involve B2C, B2B, and B2G segments benefiting from enhanced services and products.</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading2-4">Why 5G?</h2>



<p>If you are still unsure whether 5G is an excellent business opportunity or not, here are the reasons 5G is becoming a prominent technology globally.</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list list-style1">
<li><strong>Faster Speed:</strong> One of the most significant benefits when referring to 5G is its speed improvement. Imagine downloading a high-resolution within a second!</li>



<li><strong>Lower latency:</strong> 5G’s latency is faster than 1 millisecond – faster than the speed of human visual processing. Low latency allows remote device control to happen in near real-time, innovating the Internet of Things and other machine-to-machine communications, as well as providing smooth entertainment experiences like augmented reality (AR) and virtual reality (VR).</li>



<li><strong>Stronger Capacities:</strong> Speed and lower latency are exciting news. But are there any other implications the technology has for business innovations? 5G delivers 1000 times more capacity compared to 4G, meaning hundreds or thousands of connected devices communicate smoothly. Streamlined supply chain management, remote patient monitoring, smart cities, and smart homes will be able to grow even further.</li>



<li><strong>More Bandwidth:</strong> More data will be transmitted with 5G compared to the pre-existing networks. 5G can handle a spike in traffic smoothly &#8211; so events with large audiences no longer need to worry about sudden interruptions. For businesses, the technology facilitates the utilization of big data and data analytical insights.</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading2-5">Opportunities Posed by 5G &#8211; Emerging Markets, New Businesses and Investments</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading3-1">Facilitating IoT and Smart Technologies</h3>



<p>Enhanced capacity, efficiency, and extensive data utilization make 5G a great match for IoT and other smart technologies in logistics and agriculture.</p>



<p>To be specific, the integration of IoT and 5G technologies supports predictive maintenance, smart factories, and monitoring of equipment performance, worker safety, production processes, etc.</p>



<p>Seamless connectivity is also utilized in agriculture. 5G enhanced capabilities facilitate precise farming techniques, automated farming machinery, and livestock monitoring.</p>



<p>Smart cities and smart homes are other applications of IoT and smart technologies. 5G acts as the primary connectivity for home automation, health and energy management, infrastructure maintenance, and more. It can also be used with other advanced technology like AI voice assistants.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading3-2">Transforming Customer Experiences</h3>



<p>5G not only paves the way for dramatic transformation in business operations but also in the customer’s interactions and experiences.</p>



<p>Customers can enjoy VR and AR in gaming and retail events for immersive shopping experiences. They can even enjoy the extended realities from the comfort of their homes without any lagging or buffering.</p>



<p>With content creation becoming an emerging industry, 5G allows customers to enjoy high-definition content without any annoying lagging.</p>



<p>In short, 5G opens up massive opportunities to elevate and innovate customer experience, which ultimately grows the business’ revenue.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading3-3">Crowd Management</h3>



<p>Crowd management systems need a reliable connection and ultra-wideband solutions to provide real-time analytics and updates like crowd density, access control at gates, and stronger communication to allow event personnel to respond quickly in cases of emergencies.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading3-4">Fixed Wireless Access</h3>



<p>An important application of 5G is Fixed Wireless Access (FWA), which offers high-speed internet access to homes and businesses without the requirement for traditional wired connections.</p>



<p>This gives underserved areas a cost-effective and flexible solution for broadband connectivity. The technology bridges the digital gap, enabling widespread access to modern tools and services.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading3-5">Accelerating Digital Transformation</h3>



<p>5G is a gateway to elevating other digital services and technologies. It is the force driving the advancement of AI, blockchain, IoT, AR, VR technologies, and more. There is almost no limit to how 5G can be used to push other technologies forward &#8211; as its reduced latency, robust data collection, and data analytics capability are setting new standards to help businesses thrive and gain a competitive advantage.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading3-6">Supercharge Remote Work</h3>



<p>We have been witnessing a steady rise in the trend of remote working. Many are convinced that remote work is here to stay. To make the transition to new working methods easier, 5G supports strong and reliable connections, facilitating smooth video conferencing and efficient collaborations.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading3-7">Data-Driven Business Insights</h3>



<p>We have discussed extensively how 5G along with other advanced technology assists the monitoring and management of multiple devices in different industries. This process often equates with an ocean of data collected. However, that doesn’t mean all the data is analyzed. With 5G’s advanced capabilities, your business will gain valuable insights into its operations.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading3-8">Revolutionize Online Shopping</h3>



<p>Online shopping has become an integrated part of our daily lives. As the e-commerce market grows increasingly competitive, providing a seamless, lag-free shopping experience with AR try-ons and instant payments is essential to keeping customers happy.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading3-9">Real-Time Marketing Adaptation</h3>



<p>Marketing nowadays requires agility and adaptability. 5G’s reduced latency allows your business to stay on top of the latest trends in the industry.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading3-10">Telemedicine Capabilities</h3>



<p>The pandemic has boosted the growth of telemedicine – remote patient video consultation sessions as well as patient monitoring with the help of wearable devices.</p>



<p>Minimum latency is quite literally life-saving to these patients &#8211; as sometimes, being notified on time or not can make the difference between life and death.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading2-6">Last Note</h2>



<p>5G undoubtedly delivers an array of desirable features and benefits. However, the network coverage is still quite limited. Besides, 5G security concerns and vulnerabilities have people feeling unsure of the technology.</p>



<p>But don’t let these woes stop you from leveraging the latest technologies. Here at Orient Software, we pride ourselves on alleviating these woes for our customers and providing them with the latest, secure technology to meet their needs. If you would like a consultation session with us, let us know, and we will be more than happy to assist you in the journey ahead.</p><p>The post <a href="/top-10-promising-5g-business-opportunities/">Top 10 Promising 5G Business Opportunities</a> first appeared on <a href="">Seabed2crest</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/top-10-promising-5g-business-opportunities/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Exploring the Benefits of Digital Transformation</title>
		<link>/exploring-the-benefits-of-digital-transformation/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=exploring-the-benefits-of-digital-transformation</link>
					<comments>/exploring-the-benefits-of-digital-transformation/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[root]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 02:28:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Business Innovation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://live.21lab.co/kiraz/?p=40</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The world has witnessed significant digital transformations in the span of only a few years. Technology now plays a critical role in any business strategy rather than just a cost-effective solution. You have probably heard of the increased concern regarding Artificial Intelligence (AI) in our daily lives or how 3D printing has managed to accomplish [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/exploring-the-benefits-of-digital-transformation/">Exploring the Benefits of Digital Transformation</a> first appeared on <a href="">Seabed2crest</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The world has witnessed significant digital transformations in the span of only a few years. Technology now plays a critical role in any business strategy rather than just a cost-effective solution. You have probably heard of the increased concern regarding Artificial Intelligence (AI) in our daily lives or how 3D printing has managed to accomplish incredible designs. The use of technology, or in other words, digital transformation on both business-level and industry levels &#8211; has become one of the deciding factors towards success.</p>



<p>Therefore, let’s explore the benefits of digital transformation in-depth, setting aside any worries about how digital technology might someday replace humans.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Why Does Digital Transformation Matter?</h2>



<p>The first and foremost reason is that the current business and economic circumstances require the practice of new strategies &#8211; one of them is utilizing technology to gain a competitive advantage. As reported by Gartner, 87% of senior business leaders acknowledge that digitalization is a priority nowadays, and 91% of organizations of different sizes are currently involved in some digital processes. Market pressures are the main forces behind digital transformation, according to Prophet, as 51% of the efforts result from growth prospects and 41% from heightened competition.</p>



<p>Not only is the digital transformation of strategic importance for companies, but it also is needed to meet customers’ expectations. Users and buyers now expect seamless digital experiences on websites or applications.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Benefits of Digital Transformation</h2>



<p>As the presence of digital solutions becomes so ubiquitous, it’s easy to overlook the multiple benefits it has brought into our daily lives.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Data-driven Insights</h3>



<p>Digital technologies have long been used for data collection &#8211; they allow data collection to be accurate and centralized. One can access business-critical data using the right digital tools.</p>



<p>Nonetheless, the collected raw data only has meaning once it is going through analysis. Here is where you can see real-life digital transformation benefits &#8211; it provides you with the right tools to create a system and gain data-based insights. You will be presented with a single picture of operations, production, finances, and commercial prospects for the customer journey. From there, you can use this knowledge to adjust your business tactics as needed.</p>



<p>On another note, cyber theft is a continuing serious problem. Make sure you take proper measures to protect the sensitive data collected. Moreover, let your customers know how their data is being used &#8211; customers are becoming increasingly aware of how their private data is gathered and exploited. Show them you respect their privacy.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Less Human Error</h3>



<p>Most manual data processes are error-prone. Such errors are, in today’s digital age, time-consuming, expensive, and sometimes even downright dangerous. Security gaps may pose massive threats to the existence of the company itself. It is critical to minimize such risks.</p>



<p>The use of digital tools is critical to limiting such errors. They do so by flagging any abnormal activities instantly, controlling access, and setting up protective barriers.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Boost Productivity</h3>



<p>The automation of numerous manual procedures, streamlining of business processes, and integration of data empower your team members to work harder and encourage them to utilize technology on a daily basis. Ultimately, this leads to increased productivity. You might not see the difference right away, but once the compound effects start to show, you will notice the difference.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Better Customer Insights</h3>



<p>Data-driven insights lead to better customer insights. From there, you are given the tools and information to make data-driven decisions to further enhance product and service quality. The business operations revolve around your customer’s needs and feedback.</p>



<p>In order to really accelerate business growth, it is a good idea to utilize both structured and unstructured data (like social media data).</p>



<p>By actively analyzing the data and making suitable adjustments, along with smoother business operations, you are also improving customer experience. Customer experience seems to be the new battleground &#8211; businesses are fiercely competing to win their customers’ satisfaction and positive reviews.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Increased Agility in Software Development</h3>



<p>Agile methodologies are preferred and used across a large number of companies these days. Agile data-driven management software management solution that encourages adaptability and ongoing business intelligence use.</p>



<p>Digital transformation has led to the automation of important processes. Such automation can create a revolution in business operations by quickly generating core engineering metrics and establishing baselines. Automation also means that there are higher requirements regarding product quality and product performance.</p>



<p>With such a goal in mind, product managers make use of digital transformation to lower the number of bugs found throughout the DevOps process, enhance unit testing coverage, raise the number of code reviews, and boost overall stability.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Encourages a Healthy Digital Culture</h3>



<p>One of the many benefits of digital transformation is it creates a healthy digital culture for employees. By providing the right tools suitable for the existing tasks and even future workload, a lot of overhead is reduced (e.g., instead of back-and-forth emailing to determine the best time frame for a meeting, checking available time slots on a digital calendar would quickly give you the answer), giving employees the time and space to focus on value-driven activities.</p>



<p>Such advantages encourage teammates to learn and upgrade their digital skills in the short term and leverage the benefits of digital transformation in the long term.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Better Compliance</h3>



<p>Each industry, each client even, has their unique set of regulations and standards. Not complying with such regulations may lead to financial penalties. Individually, they might seem minor &#8211; but if such carelessness continues, they become extremely expensive &#8211; which eventually has negative effects on the bottom line.</p>



<p>Your company reputation then might suffer, too. Major partners then might think twice before choosing to work with you. That’s when digital transformation gives you the tools to gain visibility into your processes, products, and performance to make the right adjustments.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Innovative Business Models</h3>



<p>Digital transformation is more than enhancing and streamlining existing products or procedures. It is also innovative &#8211; looking for fresh lenses to drive growth or even completely new revenue streams for the company.</p>



<p>Furthermore, the constant adaption to technology leads to new business models being created to meet customers’ needs.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Examples of Digital Transformation Benefits in Real Life</h2>



<p>If you still find digital transformation and the future of digital growth as something on a large scale only and unrealistic, let us show you some real-life, close-to-home examples in three different industries.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Digital Transformation in Food and Beverage</h3>



<p>Any frequent Internet user has probably seen chatbots at least once during their Internet surfing sessions. Chatbots, specifically those with the help of Artificial Intelligence, have opened up new potential for businesses.</p>



<p>Domino Pizza is one such business. Its chatbot allows those with a Domino’s Pizza account to make use of Facebook Messenger to place a repeat order for a previous pizza or order their usual selection. Additionally, users receive continuous information on the progress of their pizza and may follow it from preparation through delivery.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Digital Transformation in the Supply Chain</h3>



<p>Visibility in the supply chain is imperative. One way to achieve it is by using IoT (Internet of Things) sensors on trucks, ships, and cargo containers. The sensors provide companies with information regarding locations in real-time and the conditions of goods.</p>



<p>This allows business owners to make sure the transportation is going to plan and have timely solutions should any unexpected situations come up.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Digital Transformation in Software Development</h3>



<p>Microsoft has also become aware of the major benefits of digital transformation. The business has made itself more accessible to mobile devices by offering, for instance, Office for iPad. Furthermore, the organization partners with Dropbox, expanding its OndeDdrive service, and Red Hat, a software company that provides open-source software products.</p>



<p>Not stopping there, the enterprise has also acquired LinkedIn and GitHub, creating new revenue streams for the company in the age of digital transformation.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Final Note</h2>



<p>An organization that enables future digital growth enables itself one step closer to innovating your business operation. Understanding and seeing a successful digital transformation journey is one thing &#8211; you also need a clear business strategy for digital transformation to avoid expensive and time-consuming pitfalls.</p>



<p>Don’t let your digital transformation efforts turn to nothing. Always consult experts before you decide to follow through with any long-term digital transformation strategy, especially when you are at a loss and don’t know where to start. Those with years of experience and testimonials from trusted partners are the ones you should go for, like the Orient Software team.</p><p>The post <a href="/exploring-the-benefits-of-digital-transformation/">Exploring the Benefits of Digital Transformation</a> first appeared on <a href="">Seabed2crest</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/exploring-the-benefits-of-digital-transformation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Future of Technology in 50 Years to Come</title>
		<link>/the-future-of-technology-in-50-years-to-come/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=the-future-of-technology-in-50-years-to-come</link>
					<comments>/the-future-of-technology-in-50-years-to-come/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[root]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 02:21:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Business Innovation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology Trends]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://live.21lab.co/kiraz/?p=37</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Trying to predict the future can be risky. Get it wrong, then your predictions come across as silly and far-fetched. Some good examples of this include meals in pill form, flying cars (we’re getting close though), and teleportation. Get it right, though, and you could be seen as an innovator ahead of your time. A [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/the-future-of-technology-in-50-years-to-come/">The Future of Technology in 50 Years to Come</a> first appeared on <a href="">Seabed2crest</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Trying to predict the future can be risky. Get it wrong, then your predictions come across as silly and far-fetched. Some good examples of this include meals in pill form, flying cars (we’re getting close though), and teleportation.</p>



<p>Get it right, though, and you could be seen as an innovator ahead of your time. A good example is Arthur C. Clarke, who, in his 1968 novel 2001: A Space Odyssey, accurately predicted the concept of the computer tablet with the fictional News Pad device.</p>



<p>With that being said, even if not all predictions are correct, there’s still value in fantasizing about the future. In fact, research has shown that thinking about the future helps us lead more generous and fulfilled lives, as it gives people something to look forward to and a sense of meaning.</p>



<p>This logic also applies to technology. It’s important to think about where technology is today, how it will change in the future, what it will replace, and the kind of role it will play in helping us live our lives. Why? Because it enables us to focus our efforts on making technological advancements that will vastly increase human capability and help shape a better tomorrow.</p>



<p>Have you ever wondered about the picture of technology in 50 years to come? Let’s take a look at some of the most promising technological advancements on the horizon.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading2-1">What Will the Next 50 Years Look Like?</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading3-1">#1 Self-driving Cars</h3>



<p>Self-driving cars have the potential to take us where we need to go without us ever having to set foot on the pedal. The advent of autonomous vehicles is no longer a new concept, but we’re not quite there yet due to various limitations in technological advancements.</p>



<p>The gap between manual and automatic driving is closing. You can buy cars that automatically brake when they predict a collision, have built-in cameras that monitor the driver for signs of fatigue, drowsiness or distractions, and keep you in the center of a highway lane. Specific examples for the highest level of automation available to consumers are systems such as GM’s Super Cruise, Ford Motor, Co.’s BlueCruise and Tesla’s with automated operating systems under certain conditions.</p>



<p>With big players – Tesla, Waymo, Ford, General Motors, and more – investing in the autonomous-related technology, the rise in competition in the future is inevitable and pushes the growth potential of automotive industries to the maximum level.</p>



<p>How long until autonomous cars become standard to redefine transportation systems? It’s hard to say, but most experts think full automation is possible within the next ten years. Of course, this depends on advancements in technology, government regulations, safety and ethical concerns, and public perception. It is worth noting that the transition to autonomous vehicles is a long journey, with varying levels of automation being introduced incrementally to lead to the final result.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading3-2">#2 Greater Involvement from Robots</h3>



<p>These days, robots can only perform a certain amount of tasks. They don’t really look or talk convincingly enough to pass off as human. And they tend to fall over a lot.</p>



<p>However, as digital life lays a foundation for limitless possibilities, things could be different in the future. According to Blake Hannaford, a professor of Robots, Controls, and Biosystems at the University of Washington, robots could ‘free up people’s brains’ to perform other, more complex tasks.</p>



<p>If true, you can expect to see more jobs become automated (where employees help the robot perform a specific task or work together with one) or simply disappear. This could mean up to 120 million workers will need retraining in order to be employable again.</p>



<p>On the plus side, we could use robots to perform tasks that are too dangerous for us. For instance, instead of putting the lives of rescue workers at risk, they can instead dispatch all-terrain robots to collect and return people back to safety. In a more distant future, some predictions even suggest that the U.S. Congress will be supported by a dynamic network model accounting for the concerns of citizens yet bound by established laws and resource constraints.</p>



<p>While a world full of robots capable of completely replacing humans may seem like a distant future when many unsolved issues such as ethical considerations, societal acceptance, and regulatory frameworks still exist, the evolution of technology like hybrid human networked intelligence has the potential to push the robotic industry to its boundaries. By combining human intelligence and artificial intelligence, humans create a synergistic system that leverages the strengths of both humans and machines.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading3-3">#3 Personalized Technological Experiences</h3>



<p>Companies like Amazon, Google, and Facebook already collect your private data to personalize the shopping experience.</p>



<p>Thanks to advancements in predictive AI, technology will get better at knowing what you want. By automatically analyzing vast user datasets, including your viewing and purchase history, providers can predict your unique habits and then anticipate your next move by sending you product recommendations, further enhancing engagement and satisfaction.</p>



<p>Immersive virtual and augmented reality environments will also play a significant role in offering customers personalized experiences. Imagine browsing Ikea and then seeing what that new couch will look like in your living room before you buy it. With the advent of VR web browsing, companies will soon be able to blur the lines between physical and digital realms and provide a more genuine, authentic, and engaging experience in digital life.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading3-4">#4 Beyond 5G</h3>



<p>5G is just around the corner. However, researchers are already exploring the possibilities of 6G and beyond.</p>



<p>While 5G aims to deliver increased speed, low latency, and more seamless connectivity between devices – i.e. self-driving cars and drones –, experts are already quick to point out its limitations.</p>



<p>For starters, 5G frequency waves can only travel a short distance and cannot penetrate buildings, trees, power lines, or other structures. This severely limits the potential reach of the 5G network. Secondly, 5G drains the batteries on phones and other devices faster than 4G.</p>



<p>According to experts, the next generation, 6G with expanded Internet access, will likely be powerful enough to give rise to emerging technologies like tactile internet, holographic communications, and machine-type communications.</p>



<p>Furthermore, there are predictions that the likes of 6G and beyond could deliver incredible speeds of 1TB per second, or 8,000 gigabits per second. As a reference, that means you could download around 142 hours’ worth of Netflix movies in just one second.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading3-5">#5 Body Implants</h3>



<p>Wearable devices like smartwatches, wristbands, and earbuds are all highly practical and, in some cases, fashionable. In the near-future, you can expect to see a transition to more ‘penetrative’ technology, such as microchipping, augmentations, and various other implants.</p>



<p>Sound far-fetched? You can already get a microchip in your arm to perform cashless payments in stores and at ATMs. Famous model Viktoria Modesta underwent leg amputation at the age of 20 to have her damaged leg replaced with an artificial one. She says the leg not only frees her of pain and discomfort and allows her to live a normal life, but she also uses the prosthetic leg as a memorable fashion statement.</p>



<p>With examples like this, we can expect to see wider adoption of prosthetics and brain-computer interfaces in the future and a wider variety of designs, colors, and concepts to better suit one’s taste, style, and accessibility needs. It could open up a whole new untapped market in the beauty and sports industry and beyond.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading3-6">#6 Emerging Smart Cities</h3>



<p>Smart cities are no longer a new concept, as this development model has appeared in most countries in recent years.</p>



<p>What makes a city smart? Basically, smart cities are urban models that apply advanced technologies and large amounts of data to reduce daily inefficiency and optimize city functions, thereby enhancing living standards. Although the core purpose of this smart living model has remained the same over time, the increasing demand for quality of life has made expectations for smart cities increasingly high.</p>



<p>If, at the present time, smart cities that serve human needs well are barely urban landscapes that prioritize IoT sensors, sustainability initiatives, high-speed connectivity, and smart traffic management systems, Smart cities in the future of the next 50 years are expected to integrate a number of other advanced technologies for efficiency enhancement.</p>



<p>Fully autonomous vehicles and drones will transform urban mobility and reshape the transportation network with unsurpassed levels of safety and intelligence. Augmented reality technology will be widely used to visualize and test urban design concepts in real-time before official deployment. Artificial intelligence and predictive analytics will play a more vital role in services personalization and weather prediction of the natural world, improving quality of life for residents as a whole.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading3-7">#7 Biotechnological Breakthrough in Healthcare</h3>



<p>Have you ever thought about a scenario where doctors predicted your heart attack before you had it? Biotechnology solutions have long been evaluated as the future technology for promoting human health and innovation in all segments.</p>



<p>As the volume of data coming from diverse sources such as life-style information and electronic health records increases (so called “big data”), the rosy picture of further opportunities for biotechnology becomes more apparent. What is more, this biological big data, coupled with continuous innovations in genetic engineering, molecular biology, and bioinformatics, is also expanding the capabilities of biotechnology 50 years later.</p>



<p>Ben Shneiderman, distinguished professor and founder of the Human Computer Interaction Lab at the University of Maryland, said, “Medical systems that collect patient data will give richer portraits of individual health as well as data to develop new treatment protocols.”</p>



<p>By using artificial intelligence and big data analytics tools, hospitals can completely turn raw data into actionable insights used for patient diagnosis and treatment.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading3-8">#8 Decentralized Finance (DeFi) Platforms</h3>



<p>Blockchain-based DeFi platforms could revolutionize traditional banking services by offering financial activities, including lending, borrowing, and trading options, without the help of intermediaries.</p>



<p>At present, these types of decentralized platforms are actively operating within the cryptocurrency and blockchain ecosystem. However, many concerns surrounding blockchain technology’s security and legal issues still exist, causing DeFi not truly to maximize its development potential.</p>



<p>Predicting the exact future of blockchain-based Decentralized Finance (DeFi) platforms 50 years from now is inherently challenging due to the changing nature of technology and the complex interplay of various factors shaping the future of finance. However, one thing we can confirm is that DeFi platforms, along with blockchain technology, will become more mature in the next 50 years.</p>



<p>Besides layer 2 solutions and cross-chain interoperability, which can enhance the scalability and efficiency of DeFi platforms, we expect continuous innovation in smart contract development that will be able to form more sophisticated and secure DeFi protocols. The constantly evolving blockchain algorithm is the foundation for eliminating uncertainties and doubts about this technology.</p>



<p>Once regulatory clarity and frameworks for DeFi are formed, the time where DeFi platforms become more integrated into the mainstream financial ecosystem, even extending beyond finance to appear in other sectors like healthcare will be in the not too distant future.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading2-2">The Bright Future Is in Our Hands</h2>



<p>Technology moves at an incredibly fast pace. What is popular today may be obsolete in just a few years. What was once thought impossible could become standard in less than a decade.</p>



<p>For this reason, it’s hard to know whether these predictions will come true. But it’ll be interesting to see how these ideas manifest in the years to come. Regardless of the technology scenario in 50 years, we believe that the rapid changes and developments of technological advancements are all aimed at a single ultimate goal: improving human existence and making the digital and physical worlds better.</p>



<p>It is worth noting that perfection is a far-reaching concept at all times. It cannot be denied that the future promises many positive outcomes. However, existing alongside new opportunities is a potential challenge. As humans willingly trade discretion in increasingly ubiquitous digital systems for improved quality of life, personal privacy has the potential to become a distant memory.</p>



<p>In the era of internet-enabled technology, indirect interaction through social networking platforms and communication tools unintentionally creates many security holes. If you do not nurture and maintain unmediated human relationships but rely on mostly unregulated internet, plus commercial impetus remains dominant, and international regulation remains weak, people giving away their data for convenience access has the potential to cause dangerous disruptions across society.</p>



<p>For the time being, what we can do is monitor the development of technology, watch the market trends, and listen to the experts who are involved in their development to protect personal information and minimize cybersecurity attacks.</p>



<p>You don’t have to be a scientist to contribute to a bright picture of our future’s physical and digital worlds. Instead, integrating the latest technologies in software projects is a viable way to create value across various industries and domains. What changes do you anticipate in the digital world’s platform companies? If you have an innovative business idea that cannot wait to be put into action, connect with our experts at Orient Software and learn how we can help.</p><p>The post <a href="/the-future-of-technology-in-50-years-to-come/">The Future of Technology in 50 Years to Come</a> first appeared on <a href="">Seabed2crest</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/the-future-of-technology-in-50-years-to-come/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Key Software Developer Skills in Demand</title>
		<link>/key-software-developer-skills-in-demand/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=key-software-developer-skills-in-demand</link>
					<comments>/key-software-developer-skills-in-demand/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[root]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 02:10:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Software Developer]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://live.21lab.co/kiraz/?p=30</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The world of work is changing. High growth startups and scale-ups are transitioning away from permanent hires and embracing more flexible and temporary remote working models.  This is being reflected when it comes to sourcing technical skills too. Rather than hiring permanent software developers, they are instead looking at more flexible solutions that allow them to [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/key-software-developer-skills-in-demand/">Key Software Developer Skills in Demand</a> first appeared on <a href="">Seabed2crest</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The world of work is changing. High growth startups and scale-ups are transitioning away from permanent hires and embracing more flexible and temporary remote working models. </p>



<p>This is being reflected when it comes to sourcing technical skills too. Rather than hiring permanent software developers, they are instead looking at more flexible solutions that allow them to develop products and solutions faster, and fill critical technical skills gaps at speed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Finding high quality developers is easier said than done. There’s plenty of developers out in the market, but identifying the select few who have a valuable technical skillset is the challenge for most CTOs.</p>



<p>So what makes for a high quality software developer in 2020? What developer skills should CTOs be looking out for in order to hire or work with the best talent out there?&nbsp;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">There’s No Substitute for Knowledge</h3>



<p>To meet the needs of highly niche technical job roles, first and foremost, software developers require extreme depth of knowledge in their respective field.&nbsp;</p>



<p>They need to be on the cutting edge, have a good understanding of common problems and be able to proactively overcome challenges regularly faced in their area of expertise.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On top of that, they also need to be great communicators with superb time management that can learn quickly and work well with others, all while maintaining a high-end user focus.&nbsp;</p>



<p>To operate at an elite level, developers will need to have 3 key skills in particular to deliver value for the most innovative of businesses.&nbsp;</p>



<p>These primarily include:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list list-style1">
<li>Problem solving</li>



<li>Managing data</li>



<li>Algorithm management</li>
</ul>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Assess Developer Soft Skills to Ensure Culture Fit</h3>



<p>Beyond technical skills and qualifications, high quality developers should show a good level of humility and relational smarts, while also being prepared to work in a cohesive team and offer complements when relevant.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Attitude also plays an important role. With the changing nature of high growth businesses, developers need to be open minded and eager to build their knowledge. Their mindset must reflect this philosophy and they must also be keen to seek out problems and find solutions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The best developers hired in the world’s fastest growing companies embrace the idea of shared code-ownership and are open to new ideas and recommendations on how they can improve.&nbsp;</p>



<p>These softer skills are just as important as the development talent.&nbsp;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Mastering Programming Languages&nbsp;</h3>



<p>Beyond the softer skills which help developers fit comfortably into a companies’ culture, high quality developers will have a comprehensive knowledge of at least one programming language.</p>



<p>The 5 most in demand programming languages right now are:</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Javascript</h4>



<p>Appearing in over 14% of job postings on Indeed, JavaScript skills remain in high demand. As the most-used programming language, it’s in a state of constant evolution. Operating across multiple industries and roles, Javascript remains a critical language in the development sector.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Java</h4>



<p>A mainstay of Android mobile development, Java has been a popular skill for software engineers for over two decades. Working across platforms, and allowing companies to develop code on one system and run it with other compatible machines, Java’s flexibility maintains its popularity in development projects.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Python</h4>



<p>As the fastest growing development language, Python is playing a rapidly growing role in the development sector and is a significant technology in data science. Offering versatility, simple ease of use and fast development times, Python is set to grow even further into the future, making it an increasingly critical language.&nbsp;</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Node.js</h4>



<p>Node.js is a programming language that’s in high demand right now. This shift in demand is largely due to the growth of data-intensive IOT devices and applications that are best built using Node.js.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The benefits offered by Node.JS such as unparalleled scalability, less development time and the need for a fewer number of servers, has led to it becoming an ideal choice for tech companies &amp; developers alike.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">SQL</h4>



<p>Present in 22% of all tech job postings, SQL is an absolutely critical technical skill. As the most universal database language, SQL powers many commonly used database engines. Used by technical, marketing and sales teams, SQL data has a diverse range of functions that are used to inform key business decisions, making it essential.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Seek a healthy blend of hard and soft skills</h4>



<p>Understanding one of these languages is critical as most job roles will be reliant on the developer’s knowledge of their specialist area. Each has its own unique rules, best practices and strengths and so developers need to know how to make the most of their specialist language’s capabilities.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Python, Javascript and Java are particularly sought after in the market and are often considered to be most engineer’s preferred coding languages due to their useful and well-maintained libraries and packages.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Beyond deep expertise in their field, developers must also possess other key skills and knowledge that enable them to fulfil the responsibilities of a technical role. A healthy blend of hard and soft skills is essential for any software developer to fully contribute to your team.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Familiarity With Source Control&nbsp;</h3>



<p>As a key part of software development, source control plays a major role in the management and delivery of technical projects. With teamwork being a key component in the successful delivery of technical work, source control is critical as it gives developers a way to work on the same code at the same time, without destroying each other’s contributions.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>With such a significant role in successful project delivery, it’s essential developers know how to check code in and out, and merge any changes made from multiple sources.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In addition, developers should be very familiar with at least one source control system and the basic concepts involved.&nbsp;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Concept Tools for Source Control</h3>



<p>Developers must also be familiar with the concept tools regularly used in source control.&nbsp;</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Git&nbsp;</h4>



<p>Git is the most widely used source control system. The majority of developers are familiar with it due to its widespread use. The system uses a distributed architecture and is designed to prioritise performance, security and flexibility.&nbsp;</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Mercurial SCM</h4>



<p>Mercurial is a commonly used source control system that can be easily customised to meet the requirements of the job. It’s functionality can be changed as and when required and uses a decentralised model to support multiple workflows at the same time.&nbsp;</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Subversion (SVN)&nbsp;</h4>



<p>SVN is the most popular centralised version control system. In this system, all files and historical data is stored on a central server. Whenever developers make changes, they are reflected in the centralised repository.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Developers must be able to work with both centralised and decentralised version control systems and understand their strengths and weaknesses as they play an essential role in technical development projects.&nbsp;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Using Integrated Development Environments (IDEs)</h3>



<p>Integrated development environments allow developers to write, modify, compile, run and debug their code. As such, they play a critical role in the development of technical projects and are fundamental tools to ensure high quality and consistent code.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Typically IDEs not only improve code quality but also speed up development and help maximise the value of the developer’s output.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Different development languages often have different IDE programmes and developers who know their stuff will be familiar with the IDE that matches their skill set.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For C, C++ and C# developers, Visual Studio or Code::Blocks are typically used. For Python developers Spyder, Jupyter and Pycharm are commonplace. Finally, for Java professionals, Netbeans, Eclipse and IntelliJ IDEA are considered to be the most valuable.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Whatever development language technical professionals use, they must be familiar with the relevant IDE, this plays a key role in optimising their quality of their work.&nbsp;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Understanding How Databases Work&nbsp;</h3>



<p>Working with databases is a fundamental part of any developer’s role. Technical professionals should know how to store, create, insert, update and delete records when necessary. All application and software development requires some form of database usage and so developers need to be able to use them efficiently and this requires a comprehensive knowledge.&nbsp;</p>



<p>A quality developer should know more than just how to use a database, but also to make the most of the value it can offer in a project. For example, backing database contents up to ensure data is not lost and is secure.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The best developers should know how to work with multiple SQL queries as different companies will often be running different databases, including;&nbsp;</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list list-style1">
<li>Oracle</li>



<li>PostgreSQL</li>



<li>MongoDB</li>



<li>Cassandra</li>



<li>Redis</li>
</ul>



<p>Database management and use is a key developer skill, and plays an essential role in the effective delivery of a technical project.&nbsp;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Knowing the Nuances of Different Operating Systems&nbsp;</h3>



<p>Different operating systems work in different ways and so developers should understand the nuances of each. This is a key skill as it will often fundamentally change the requirements, challenges and opportunities involved in a development project.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The 3 essential operating systems developers need to know are Linux, Windows and Mac. In most instances development will require compatibility across these 3 in particular. However, if the technical project is designed for mobile or tablet devices, then the developer needs to be familiar with Android and iOS as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Whatever the requirements, understanding the differences between operating systems is crucial, as when problems arise, developers need to know whether the OS is playing a role and how it can be tested, as this will help identify and solve the problem.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In addition, experienced developers will likely have previous knowledge of issues caused by OS in product development and this familiarity may help them to overcome challenges faster.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Operating systems play a major in technical projects and so understanding how they work is an essential developer skill that helps to maximise the efficiency of delivery.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">An Appreciation of Basic Testing&nbsp;</h3>



<p>Testing plays a major role in the software development process, ensuring code achieves the necessary functionality and meets the required standards. Testing also ensures errors are flagged early and faulty output is avoided wherever possible. This is particularly important when developing a new product from the ground up and showcases why it’s such an important developer skill.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Testing comes in many forms and developers need to understand them all to effectively test their output and ensure they’re meeting the necessary standards.&nbsp;</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Code Quality Review</h4>



<p>The code quality review plays a key part of the quality assurance process, bringing programmers together in order to review code from multiple perspectives.&nbsp;</p>



<p>By having a fresh pair of eyes review the code, mistakes and errors can be quickly identified and rectified. These peer reviews save time by streamlining the development process up-front and significantly reduce the strain on quality assurance teams at the end of the project.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Developers must be able to review other developer’s code and find mistakes as they will play a key role in not only checking their own output, but others too.&nbsp;</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Unit Testing&nbsp;</h4>



<p>Unit testing is the evaluation of individual components of a piece of software. It is designed to ensure all pieces of a technical project are performing their function optimally and help break the overall testing process down to find errors.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Most units that are tested often have few inputs and only a single output. Developers need to be familiar with unit testing frameworks that are relevant to their development language alongside, drivers, stubs and mock objects. These all play a major role in the unit testing process.&nbsp;</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Integration Testing&nbsp;</h4>



<p>Following on from unit testing, developers must also be familiar with integration testing. This expands on the unit testing approach and involves multiple units, evaluating the interaction between them to ensure they work cohesively and function as they are designed.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>This test looks at how data is processed and evaluates whether it functions correctly, producing the expected outputs.&nbsp;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Performance/System Testing&nbsp;</h3>



<p>Performance testing is designed to evaluate a system’s responsiveness and stability under a certain load. Developers need to ensure what they build is fit for purpose, so relative performance testing is essential.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Understanding how different system tests (load, stress, endurance and spike testing) work and the role they play in evaluating software output is a key skill for any developer. Performance is often the name of the game when it comes to building high quality technical output, so developers must be able to evaluate their work effectively.&nbsp;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Security Testing&nbsp;</h3>



<p>Security testing is designed to identify vulnerabilities in a piece of software or system.</p>



<p>Developers need to be familiar with the 4 key areas of security testing:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list list-style1">
<li><strong>Network security</strong> &#8211; Looking for vulnerabilities in the network infrastructure.</li>



<li><strong>System software security</strong> &#8211; Evaluating weaknesses in the software components, including the operating system, the database system and other software the application uses. </li>



<li><strong>Client-side application security</strong> &#8211; assessing the client/browser to ensure it cannot be manipulated. </li>



<li><strong>Server-side application security</strong> &#8211; reviewing the server code and other technologies to ensure there are no back doors. </li>
</ul>



<p>Security testing is an essential part of the overall testing process and it’s critical developers have a good familiarity of typical components involved.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Developers need to be familiar and capable to conduct all of the above tests on their technical output. This is a key skill as it ensures that what they produce is of the necessary quality and works effectively.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Understanding the Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC)&nbsp;</h2>



<p>The software development life cycle is the multi-step process used to develop reliable and high quality software with minimal errors.</p>



<p>All software developers must have a comprehensive knowledge of these stages, how they work, what’s involved in each and an understanding of how they link together.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Without an appreciation for this system and the stages involved, developers will struggle to to work to an effective development flow.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There are typically 7 steps involved in the software development life cycle:&nbsp;</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list list-style1">
<li>Requirement gathering and analysis </li>



<li>Feasibility study</li>



<li>Design</li>



<li>Implementation and coding</li>



<li>Testing </li>



<li>Deployment </li>



<li>Maintenance</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Artificial Intelligence (AI) and Machine Learning</h2>



<p>Not only is artificial intelligence a rapidly growing technology, it’s widely predicted that it will be one that has a profound impact across almost every industry in the future.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It’s therefore no surprise that developers that hiring growth for AI developers has grown 74% over the past 4 years. According to McKinsey, 49% of companies are currently exploring or planning to use machine learning.</p>



<p>As AI enabled products and services rapidly enter the market, developers with knowledge of machine learning, AI integration and AI application programming, natural language processing, and change management experience are in high demand.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Filling technical skills gaps with remote developer talent</h2>



<p>There’s no doubt that there’s a pool of talented developers in the market today whose skills match elements of those mentioned in some shape or form.</p>



<p>But for many startups and scale-ups, that talent is often difficult to access and filling technical skills gaps can be a tall order.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Elite developers capable of working with cutting edge technology are often snapped up quickly by the big technology companies. The freelance market offers up a mixed bag of developers who don’t always fit naturally into a business, or their skills just don’t meet the grade.</p>



<p>It’s for these reasons that remote development teams have become more popular in recent years as a solution to overcome technical skills gaps in high growth businesses. </p>



<p>More companies than ever are embracing cross border collaboration, building distributed teams and hiring remote workers to source the key skills they need. Other companies have fully embraced the remote philosophy, creating entire hubs of remote experts to access the talent at source.</p>



<p>However you go about filling technical skills gaps in your business, the skills listed above should help guide you towards finding the right talent or remote teams that can deliver your software development projects effectively.</p><p>The post <a href="/key-software-developer-skills-in-demand/">Key Software Developer Skills in Demand</a> first appeared on <a href="">Seabed2crest</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/key-software-developer-skills-in-demand/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
