<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Business Innovation - Seabed2crest</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/business-innovation/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 02:38:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.7</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/seabed2crest-logo.png</url>
	<title>Business Innovation - Seabed2crest</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Top 10 Promising 5G Business Opportunities</title>
		<link>/top-10-promising-5g-business-opportunities/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=top-10-promising-5g-business-opportunities</link>
					<comments>/top-10-promising-5g-business-opportunities/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[root]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 02:38:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Business Innovation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://live.21lab.co/kiraz/?p=42</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>5G has been quite the buzzword for some time. When comparing it to its predecessors, like 4G, its theoretical download speeds are ten faster. Its latency (the time it requires for data to travel from its source to the destination) is less than one millisecond. 4G’s latency is less than ten milliseconds. The latest mobile [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/top-10-promising-5g-business-opportunities/">Top 10 Promising 5G Business Opportunities</a> first appeared on <a href="">Seabed2crest</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>5G has been quite the buzzword for some time. When comparing it to its predecessors, like 4G, its theoretical download speeds are ten faster. Its latency (the time it requires for data to travel from its source to the destination) is less than one millisecond. 4G’s latency is less than ten milliseconds.</p>



<p>The latest mobile versions, like the iPhone 15 and Samsung Galaxy S24, support 5G, and it is gradually becoming the new standard for mobile devices.</p>



<p>Do faster data speeds and new standards mean better services? What implications and impacts does 5G have on business opportunities? By examining 5G, the technology’s current state of infrastructure and the roles of stakeholders will provide us with an insight into these questions.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Key Takeaways:</h3>



<ul class="wp-block-list list-style1">
<li>5G is a new-generation technology that facilitates strong and reliable connections, low latency, and increased bandwidth.</li>



<li>5G-enhanced technology paves the way for multiple business opportunities, including smart IoT technologies, seamless remote work and remote healthcare services, data-driven business decisions, accelerating digital transformation, and more.</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading2-1">An Overview of 5G Technology &#8211; What is it and How it Works</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Definition</h3>



<p>5G stands for fifth-generation mobile technology. It is the new standard for telecommunications networks. While it uses the same frequencies as 3G and 4G, it provides quicker download rates, reduced latency, and increased bandwidth, which means improved dependability, stronger connectivity, and shorter download times.</p>



<p>In addition, 5G facilitates seamless roaming between cellular and Wi-Fi networks without the need for reauthentication, improving digital activities like online gaming and videoconferencing. Its dense, distributed-access architecture brings data processing closer to users, enabling faster processing.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">How Does 5G Work?</h3>



<p>Similar to communication systems, 5G technology uses radio frequency to transmit information through air. However, it does so with a less cluttered and higher frequency.</p>



<p>High bandwidth allows 5G to carry data faster, but it also faces the challenges of traveling over long distances, which are often obstructed by buildings or trees. Numerous input and output antennae are used to boost the signal and capacity of wireless networks to solve this problem. Smaller transmitters are also placed on buildings and street furniture.</p>



<p>Another notable capability of new-generation cellular technology is its ability to “slice” physical networks. Physical network slicing enables the creation of multiple virtual networks on top of the shared network. This allows operators to “slice” the network based on the user’s demand. For example, a video streamer’s network demands are different from that of a student or a business. This agility also allows enhanced mobile broadband or enterprises to purchase their own private networks.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading2-2">A Quick Look at 5G Adoption Statistics</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Global Statistics</h3>



<ul class="wp-block-list list-style1">
<li>From 2019 to 2028, there will be a sharp rise in 5G subscribers globally, from over 12 million to over 4.5 billion, according to projections. According to region, the highest subscription rates are anticipated in North East Asia, Southeast Asia, India, Nepal, and Bhutan. (Statista)</li>



<li>Berg Insight’s research report shows 2,900 private LTE/5G networks globally deployed by 2023, with 700 networks transitioning from trials to commercial operations. The number is expected to grow at a 33% CAGR until 2028, reaching 11,900 networks. Many networks will be upgraded to 5G within the next 2-3 years.</li>



<li>By the end of 2023, around 45% of the world’s population is going to have access to 5G, and by 2029, that percentage is anticipated to rise to 85%. (Ericsson)</li>
</ul>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Vietnam Statistics</h3>



<ul class="wp-block-list list-style1">
<li>Vietnam aims to commercialize 5G nationwide in 2024. (Tuoitrenews)</li>



<li>The Government News reported that the National Institute of Information and Communications Strategy estimates, that 5G services will increase Vietnam’s GDP by about 7.34 percent by 2025.</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading2-3">The Roles of Business and Stakeholders in Transformations with 5G</h2>



<p>To truly make use of 5G business opportunities, you need to be aware of the stakeholders and their roles.</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list list-style1">
<li><strong>Network Service Providers (NSPs)</strong> develop, offer, and maintain control over infrastructure and service quality.</li>



<li><strong>Communication Service Providers (CSPs)</strong> are the ones to provide services to Online Service Providers (OSPs) and end-customers.</li>



<li><strong>Online Service Providers (OSPs)</strong>, in addition to collaborating with NSPs for secured services, deliver and represent vertical industry stakeholders (E.g., automotive, energy, health) and provide tailored products to end-users.</li>



<li><strong>Device manufacturers and network infrastructure manufacturers</strong> offer proper devices and infrastructure for network deployment.</li>



<li><strong>End-customers</strong> involve B2C, B2B, and B2G segments benefiting from enhanced services and products.</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading2-4">Why 5G?</h2>



<p>If you are still unsure whether 5G is an excellent business opportunity or not, here are the reasons 5G is becoming a prominent technology globally.</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list list-style1">
<li><strong>Faster Speed:</strong> One of the most significant benefits when referring to 5G is its speed improvement. Imagine downloading a high-resolution within a second!</li>



<li><strong>Lower latency:</strong> 5G’s latency is faster than 1 millisecond – faster than the speed of human visual processing. Low latency allows remote device control to happen in near real-time, innovating the Internet of Things and other machine-to-machine communications, as well as providing smooth entertainment experiences like augmented reality (AR) and virtual reality (VR).</li>



<li><strong>Stronger Capacities:</strong> Speed and lower latency are exciting news. But are there any other implications the technology has for business innovations? 5G delivers 1000 times more capacity compared to 4G, meaning hundreds or thousands of connected devices communicate smoothly. Streamlined supply chain management, remote patient monitoring, smart cities, and smart homes will be able to grow even further.</li>



<li><strong>More Bandwidth:</strong> More data will be transmitted with 5G compared to the pre-existing networks. 5G can handle a spike in traffic smoothly &#8211; so events with large audiences no longer need to worry about sudden interruptions. For businesses, the technology facilitates the utilization of big data and data analytical insights.</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading2-5">Opportunities Posed by 5G &#8211; Emerging Markets, New Businesses and Investments</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading3-1">Facilitating IoT and Smart Technologies</h3>



<p>Enhanced capacity, efficiency, and extensive data utilization make 5G a great match for IoT and other smart technologies in logistics and agriculture.</p>



<p>To be specific, the integration of IoT and 5G technologies supports predictive maintenance, smart factories, and monitoring of equipment performance, worker safety, production processes, etc.</p>



<p>Seamless connectivity is also utilized in agriculture. 5G enhanced capabilities facilitate precise farming techniques, automated farming machinery, and livestock monitoring.</p>



<p>Smart cities and smart homes are other applications of IoT and smart technologies. 5G acts as the primary connectivity for home automation, health and energy management, infrastructure maintenance, and more. It can also be used with other advanced technology like AI voice assistants.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading3-2">Transforming Customer Experiences</h3>



<p>5G not only paves the way for dramatic transformation in business operations but also in the customer’s interactions and experiences.</p>



<p>Customers can enjoy VR and AR in gaming and retail events for immersive shopping experiences. They can even enjoy the extended realities from the comfort of their homes without any lagging or buffering.</p>



<p>With content creation becoming an emerging industry, 5G allows customers to enjoy high-definition content without any annoying lagging.</p>



<p>In short, 5G opens up massive opportunities to elevate and innovate customer experience, which ultimately grows the business’ revenue.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading3-3">Crowd Management</h3>



<p>Crowd management systems need a reliable connection and ultra-wideband solutions to provide real-time analytics and updates like crowd density, access control at gates, and stronger communication to allow event personnel to respond quickly in cases of emergencies.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading3-4">Fixed Wireless Access</h3>



<p>An important application of 5G is Fixed Wireless Access (FWA), which offers high-speed internet access to homes and businesses without the requirement for traditional wired connections.</p>



<p>This gives underserved areas a cost-effective and flexible solution for broadband connectivity. The technology bridges the digital gap, enabling widespread access to modern tools and services.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading3-5">Accelerating Digital Transformation</h3>



<p>5G is a gateway to elevating other digital services and technologies. It is the force driving the advancement of AI, blockchain, IoT, AR, VR technologies, and more. There is almost no limit to how 5G can be used to push other technologies forward &#8211; as its reduced latency, robust data collection, and data analytics capability are setting new standards to help businesses thrive and gain a competitive advantage.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading3-6">Supercharge Remote Work</h3>



<p>We have been witnessing a steady rise in the trend of remote working. Many are convinced that remote work is here to stay. To make the transition to new working methods easier, 5G supports strong and reliable connections, facilitating smooth video conferencing and efficient collaborations.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading3-7">Data-Driven Business Insights</h3>



<p>We have discussed extensively how 5G along with other advanced technology assists the monitoring and management of multiple devices in different industries. This process often equates with an ocean of data collected. However, that doesn’t mean all the data is analyzed. With 5G’s advanced capabilities, your business will gain valuable insights into its operations.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading3-8">Revolutionize Online Shopping</h3>



<p>Online shopping has become an integrated part of our daily lives. As the e-commerce market grows increasingly competitive, providing a seamless, lag-free shopping experience with AR try-ons and instant payments is essential to keeping customers happy.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading3-9">Real-Time Marketing Adaptation</h3>



<p>Marketing nowadays requires agility and adaptability. 5G’s reduced latency allows your business to stay on top of the latest trends in the industry.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading3-10">Telemedicine Capabilities</h3>



<p>The pandemic has boosted the growth of telemedicine – remote patient video consultation sessions as well as patient monitoring with the help of wearable devices.</p>



<p>Minimum latency is quite literally life-saving to these patients &#8211; as sometimes, being notified on time or not can make the difference between life and death.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading2-6">Last Note</h2>



<p>5G undoubtedly delivers an array of desirable features and benefits. However, the network coverage is still quite limited. Besides, 5G security concerns and vulnerabilities have people feeling unsure of the technology.</p>



<p>But don’t let these woes stop you from leveraging the latest technologies. Here at Orient Software, we pride ourselves on alleviating these woes for our customers and providing them with the latest, secure technology to meet their needs. If you would like a consultation session with us, let us know, and we will be more than happy to assist you in the journey ahead.</p><p>The post <a href="/top-10-promising-5g-business-opportunities/">Top 10 Promising 5G Business Opportunities</a> first appeared on <a href="">Seabed2crest</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/top-10-promising-5g-business-opportunities/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Exploring the Benefits of Digital Transformation</title>
		<link>/exploring-the-benefits-of-digital-transformation/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=exploring-the-benefits-of-digital-transformation</link>
					<comments>/exploring-the-benefits-of-digital-transformation/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[root]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 02:28:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Business Innovation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://live.21lab.co/kiraz/?p=40</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The world has witnessed significant digital transformations in the span of only a few years. Technology now plays a critical role in any business strategy rather than just a cost-effective solution. You have probably heard of the increased concern regarding Artificial Intelligence (AI) in our daily lives or how 3D printing has managed to accomplish [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/exploring-the-benefits-of-digital-transformation/">Exploring the Benefits of Digital Transformation</a> first appeared on <a href="">Seabed2crest</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The world has witnessed significant digital transformations in the span of only a few years. Technology now plays a critical role in any business strategy rather than just a cost-effective solution. You have probably heard of the increased concern regarding Artificial Intelligence (AI) in our daily lives or how 3D printing has managed to accomplish incredible designs. The use of technology, or in other words, digital transformation on both business-level and industry levels &#8211; has become one of the deciding factors towards success.</p>



<p>Therefore, let’s explore the benefits of digital transformation in-depth, setting aside any worries about how digital technology might someday replace humans.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Why Does Digital Transformation Matter?</h2>



<p>The first and foremost reason is that the current business and economic circumstances require the practice of new strategies &#8211; one of them is utilizing technology to gain a competitive advantage. As reported by Gartner, 87% of senior business leaders acknowledge that digitalization is a priority nowadays, and 91% of organizations of different sizes are currently involved in some digital processes. Market pressures are the main forces behind digital transformation, according to Prophet, as 51% of the efforts result from growth prospects and 41% from heightened competition.</p>



<p>Not only is the digital transformation of strategic importance for companies, but it also is needed to meet customers’ expectations. Users and buyers now expect seamless digital experiences on websites or applications.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Benefits of Digital Transformation</h2>



<p>As the presence of digital solutions becomes so ubiquitous, it’s easy to overlook the multiple benefits it has brought into our daily lives.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Data-driven Insights</h3>



<p>Digital technologies have long been used for data collection &#8211; they allow data collection to be accurate and centralized. One can access business-critical data using the right digital tools.</p>



<p>Nonetheless, the collected raw data only has meaning once it is going through analysis. Here is where you can see real-life digital transformation benefits &#8211; it provides you with the right tools to create a system and gain data-based insights. You will be presented with a single picture of operations, production, finances, and commercial prospects for the customer journey. From there, you can use this knowledge to adjust your business tactics as needed.</p>



<p>On another note, cyber theft is a continuing serious problem. Make sure you take proper measures to protect the sensitive data collected. Moreover, let your customers know how their data is being used &#8211; customers are becoming increasingly aware of how their private data is gathered and exploited. Show them you respect their privacy.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Less Human Error</h3>



<p>Most manual data processes are error-prone. Such errors are, in today’s digital age, time-consuming, expensive, and sometimes even downright dangerous. Security gaps may pose massive threats to the existence of the company itself. It is critical to minimize such risks.</p>



<p>The use of digital tools is critical to limiting such errors. They do so by flagging any abnormal activities instantly, controlling access, and setting up protective barriers.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Boost Productivity</h3>



<p>The automation of numerous manual procedures, streamlining of business processes, and integration of data empower your team members to work harder and encourage them to utilize technology on a daily basis. Ultimately, this leads to increased productivity. You might not see the difference right away, but once the compound effects start to show, you will notice the difference.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Better Customer Insights</h3>



<p>Data-driven insights lead to better customer insights. From there, you are given the tools and information to make data-driven decisions to further enhance product and service quality. The business operations revolve around your customer’s needs and feedback.</p>



<p>In order to really accelerate business growth, it is a good idea to utilize both structured and unstructured data (like social media data).</p>



<p>By actively analyzing the data and making suitable adjustments, along with smoother business operations, you are also improving customer experience. Customer experience seems to be the new battleground &#8211; businesses are fiercely competing to win their customers’ satisfaction and positive reviews.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Increased Agility in Software Development</h3>



<p>Agile methodologies are preferred and used across a large number of companies these days. Agile data-driven management software management solution that encourages adaptability and ongoing business intelligence use.</p>



<p>Digital transformation has led to the automation of important processes. Such automation can create a revolution in business operations by quickly generating core engineering metrics and establishing baselines. Automation also means that there are higher requirements regarding product quality and product performance.</p>



<p>With such a goal in mind, product managers make use of digital transformation to lower the number of bugs found throughout the DevOps process, enhance unit testing coverage, raise the number of code reviews, and boost overall stability.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Encourages a Healthy Digital Culture</h3>



<p>One of the many benefits of digital transformation is it creates a healthy digital culture for employees. By providing the right tools suitable for the existing tasks and even future workload, a lot of overhead is reduced (e.g., instead of back-and-forth emailing to determine the best time frame for a meeting, checking available time slots on a digital calendar would quickly give you the answer), giving employees the time and space to focus on value-driven activities.</p>



<p>Such advantages encourage teammates to learn and upgrade their digital skills in the short term and leverage the benefits of digital transformation in the long term.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Better Compliance</h3>



<p>Each industry, each client even, has their unique set of regulations and standards. Not complying with such regulations may lead to financial penalties. Individually, they might seem minor &#8211; but if such carelessness continues, they become extremely expensive &#8211; which eventually has negative effects on the bottom line.</p>



<p>Your company reputation then might suffer, too. Major partners then might think twice before choosing to work with you. That’s when digital transformation gives you the tools to gain visibility into your processes, products, and performance to make the right adjustments.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Innovative Business Models</h3>



<p>Digital transformation is more than enhancing and streamlining existing products or procedures. It is also innovative &#8211; looking for fresh lenses to drive growth or even completely new revenue streams for the company.</p>



<p>Furthermore, the constant adaption to technology leads to new business models being created to meet customers’ needs.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Examples of Digital Transformation Benefits in Real Life</h2>



<p>If you still find digital transformation and the future of digital growth as something on a large scale only and unrealistic, let us show you some real-life, close-to-home examples in three different industries.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Digital Transformation in Food and Beverage</h3>



<p>Any frequent Internet user has probably seen chatbots at least once during their Internet surfing sessions. Chatbots, specifically those with the help of Artificial Intelligence, have opened up new potential for businesses.</p>



<p>Domino Pizza is one such business. Its chatbot allows those with a Domino’s Pizza account to make use of Facebook Messenger to place a repeat order for a previous pizza or order their usual selection. Additionally, users receive continuous information on the progress of their pizza and may follow it from preparation through delivery.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Digital Transformation in the Supply Chain</h3>



<p>Visibility in the supply chain is imperative. One way to achieve it is by using IoT (Internet of Things) sensors on trucks, ships, and cargo containers. The sensors provide companies with information regarding locations in real-time and the conditions of goods.</p>



<p>This allows business owners to make sure the transportation is going to plan and have timely solutions should any unexpected situations come up.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Digital Transformation in Software Development</h3>



<p>Microsoft has also become aware of the major benefits of digital transformation. The business has made itself more accessible to mobile devices by offering, for instance, Office for iPad. Furthermore, the organization partners with Dropbox, expanding its OndeDdrive service, and Red Hat, a software company that provides open-source software products.</p>



<p>Not stopping there, the enterprise has also acquired LinkedIn and GitHub, creating new revenue streams for the company in the age of digital transformation.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Final Note</h2>



<p>An organization that enables future digital growth enables itself one step closer to innovating your business operation. Understanding and seeing a successful digital transformation journey is one thing &#8211; you also need a clear business strategy for digital transformation to avoid expensive and time-consuming pitfalls.</p>



<p>Don’t let your digital transformation efforts turn to nothing. Always consult experts before you decide to follow through with any long-term digital transformation strategy, especially when you are at a loss and don’t know where to start. Those with years of experience and testimonials from trusted partners are the ones you should go for, like the Orient Software team.</p><p>The post <a href="/exploring-the-benefits-of-digital-transformation/">Exploring the Benefits of Digital Transformation</a> first appeared on <a href="">Seabed2crest</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/exploring-the-benefits-of-digital-transformation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Future of Technology in 50 Years to Come</title>
		<link>/the-future-of-technology-in-50-years-to-come/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=the-future-of-technology-in-50-years-to-come</link>
					<comments>/the-future-of-technology-in-50-years-to-come/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[root]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 02:21:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Business Innovation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology Trends]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://live.21lab.co/kiraz/?p=37</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Trying to predict the future can be risky. Get it wrong, then your predictions come across as silly and far-fetched. Some good examples of this include meals in pill form, flying cars (we’re getting close though), and teleportation. Get it right, though, and you could be seen as an innovator ahead of your time. A [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/the-future-of-technology-in-50-years-to-come/">The Future of Technology in 50 Years to Come</a> first appeared on <a href="">Seabed2crest</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Trying to predict the future can be risky. Get it wrong, then your predictions come across as silly and far-fetched. Some good examples of this include meals in pill form, flying cars (we’re getting close though), and teleportation.</p>



<p>Get it right, though, and you could be seen as an innovator ahead of your time. A good example is Arthur C. Clarke, who, in his 1968 novel 2001: A Space Odyssey, accurately predicted the concept of the computer tablet with the fictional News Pad device.</p>



<p>With that being said, even if not all predictions are correct, there’s still value in fantasizing about the future. In fact, research has shown that thinking about the future helps us lead more generous and fulfilled lives, as it gives people something to look forward to and a sense of meaning.</p>



<p>This logic also applies to technology. It’s important to think about where technology is today, how it will change in the future, what it will replace, and the kind of role it will play in helping us live our lives. Why? Because it enables us to focus our efforts on making technological advancements that will vastly increase human capability and help shape a better tomorrow.</p>



<p>Have you ever wondered about the picture of technology in 50 years to come? Let’s take a look at some of the most promising technological advancements on the horizon.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading2-1">What Will the Next 50 Years Look Like?</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading3-1">#1 Self-driving Cars</h3>



<p>Self-driving cars have the potential to take us where we need to go without us ever having to set foot on the pedal. The advent of autonomous vehicles is no longer a new concept, but we’re not quite there yet due to various limitations in technological advancements.</p>



<p>The gap between manual and automatic driving is closing. You can buy cars that automatically brake when they predict a collision, have built-in cameras that monitor the driver for signs of fatigue, drowsiness or distractions, and keep you in the center of a highway lane. Specific examples for the highest level of automation available to consumers are systems such as GM’s Super Cruise, Ford Motor, Co.’s BlueCruise and Tesla’s with automated operating systems under certain conditions.</p>



<p>With big players – Tesla, Waymo, Ford, General Motors, and more – investing in the autonomous-related technology, the rise in competition in the future is inevitable and pushes the growth potential of automotive industries to the maximum level.</p>



<p>How long until autonomous cars become standard to redefine transportation systems? It’s hard to say, but most experts think full automation is possible within the next ten years. Of course, this depends on advancements in technology, government regulations, safety and ethical concerns, and public perception. It is worth noting that the transition to autonomous vehicles is a long journey, with varying levels of automation being introduced incrementally to lead to the final result.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading3-2">#2 Greater Involvement from Robots</h3>



<p>These days, robots can only perform a certain amount of tasks. They don’t really look or talk convincingly enough to pass off as human. And they tend to fall over a lot.</p>



<p>However, as digital life lays a foundation for limitless possibilities, things could be different in the future. According to Blake Hannaford, a professor of Robots, Controls, and Biosystems at the University of Washington, robots could ‘free up people’s brains’ to perform other, more complex tasks.</p>



<p>If true, you can expect to see more jobs become automated (where employees help the robot perform a specific task or work together with one) or simply disappear. This could mean up to 120 million workers will need retraining in order to be employable again.</p>



<p>On the plus side, we could use robots to perform tasks that are too dangerous for us. For instance, instead of putting the lives of rescue workers at risk, they can instead dispatch all-terrain robots to collect and return people back to safety. In a more distant future, some predictions even suggest that the U.S. Congress will be supported by a dynamic network model accounting for the concerns of citizens yet bound by established laws and resource constraints.</p>



<p>While a world full of robots capable of completely replacing humans may seem like a distant future when many unsolved issues such as ethical considerations, societal acceptance, and regulatory frameworks still exist, the evolution of technology like hybrid human networked intelligence has the potential to push the robotic industry to its boundaries. By combining human intelligence and artificial intelligence, humans create a synergistic system that leverages the strengths of both humans and machines.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading3-3">#3 Personalized Technological Experiences</h3>



<p>Companies like Amazon, Google, and Facebook already collect your private data to personalize the shopping experience.</p>



<p>Thanks to advancements in predictive AI, technology will get better at knowing what you want. By automatically analyzing vast user datasets, including your viewing and purchase history, providers can predict your unique habits and then anticipate your next move by sending you product recommendations, further enhancing engagement and satisfaction.</p>



<p>Immersive virtual and augmented reality environments will also play a significant role in offering customers personalized experiences. Imagine browsing Ikea and then seeing what that new couch will look like in your living room before you buy it. With the advent of VR web browsing, companies will soon be able to blur the lines between physical and digital realms and provide a more genuine, authentic, and engaging experience in digital life.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading3-4">#4 Beyond 5G</h3>



<p>5G is just around the corner. However, researchers are already exploring the possibilities of 6G and beyond.</p>



<p>While 5G aims to deliver increased speed, low latency, and more seamless connectivity between devices – i.e. self-driving cars and drones –, experts are already quick to point out its limitations.</p>



<p>For starters, 5G frequency waves can only travel a short distance and cannot penetrate buildings, trees, power lines, or other structures. This severely limits the potential reach of the 5G network. Secondly, 5G drains the batteries on phones and other devices faster than 4G.</p>



<p>According to experts, the next generation, 6G with expanded Internet access, will likely be powerful enough to give rise to emerging technologies like tactile internet, holographic communications, and machine-type communications.</p>



<p>Furthermore, there are predictions that the likes of 6G and beyond could deliver incredible speeds of 1TB per second, or 8,000 gigabits per second. As a reference, that means you could download around 142 hours’ worth of Netflix movies in just one second.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading3-5">#5 Body Implants</h3>



<p>Wearable devices like smartwatches, wristbands, and earbuds are all highly practical and, in some cases, fashionable. In the near-future, you can expect to see a transition to more ‘penetrative’ technology, such as microchipping, augmentations, and various other implants.</p>



<p>Sound far-fetched? You can already get a microchip in your arm to perform cashless payments in stores and at ATMs. Famous model Viktoria Modesta underwent leg amputation at the age of 20 to have her damaged leg replaced with an artificial one. She says the leg not only frees her of pain and discomfort and allows her to live a normal life, but she also uses the prosthetic leg as a memorable fashion statement.</p>



<p>With examples like this, we can expect to see wider adoption of prosthetics and brain-computer interfaces in the future and a wider variety of designs, colors, and concepts to better suit one’s taste, style, and accessibility needs. It could open up a whole new untapped market in the beauty and sports industry and beyond.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading3-6">#6 Emerging Smart Cities</h3>



<p>Smart cities are no longer a new concept, as this development model has appeared in most countries in recent years.</p>



<p>What makes a city smart? Basically, smart cities are urban models that apply advanced technologies and large amounts of data to reduce daily inefficiency and optimize city functions, thereby enhancing living standards. Although the core purpose of this smart living model has remained the same over time, the increasing demand for quality of life has made expectations for smart cities increasingly high.</p>



<p>If, at the present time, smart cities that serve human needs well are barely urban landscapes that prioritize IoT sensors, sustainability initiatives, high-speed connectivity, and smart traffic management systems, Smart cities in the future of the next 50 years are expected to integrate a number of other advanced technologies for efficiency enhancement.</p>



<p>Fully autonomous vehicles and drones will transform urban mobility and reshape the transportation network with unsurpassed levels of safety and intelligence. Augmented reality technology will be widely used to visualize and test urban design concepts in real-time before official deployment. Artificial intelligence and predictive analytics will play a more vital role in services personalization and weather prediction of the natural world, improving quality of life for residents as a whole.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading3-7">#7 Biotechnological Breakthrough in Healthcare</h3>



<p>Have you ever thought about a scenario where doctors predicted your heart attack before you had it? Biotechnology solutions have long been evaluated as the future technology for promoting human health and innovation in all segments.</p>



<p>As the volume of data coming from diverse sources such as life-style information and electronic health records increases (so called “big data”), the rosy picture of further opportunities for biotechnology becomes more apparent. What is more, this biological big data, coupled with continuous innovations in genetic engineering, molecular biology, and bioinformatics, is also expanding the capabilities of biotechnology 50 years later.</p>



<p>Ben Shneiderman, distinguished professor and founder of the Human Computer Interaction Lab at the University of Maryland, said, “Medical systems that collect patient data will give richer portraits of individual health as well as data to develop new treatment protocols.”</p>



<p>By using artificial intelligence and big data analytics tools, hospitals can completely turn raw data into actionable insights used for patient diagnosis and treatment.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading3-8">#8 Decentralized Finance (DeFi) Platforms</h3>



<p>Blockchain-based DeFi platforms could revolutionize traditional banking services by offering financial activities, including lending, borrowing, and trading options, without the help of intermediaries.</p>



<p>At present, these types of decentralized platforms are actively operating within the cryptocurrency and blockchain ecosystem. However, many concerns surrounding blockchain technology’s security and legal issues still exist, causing DeFi not truly to maximize its development potential.</p>



<p>Predicting the exact future of blockchain-based Decentralized Finance (DeFi) platforms 50 years from now is inherently challenging due to the changing nature of technology and the complex interplay of various factors shaping the future of finance. However, one thing we can confirm is that DeFi platforms, along with blockchain technology, will become more mature in the next 50 years.</p>



<p>Besides layer 2 solutions and cross-chain interoperability, which can enhance the scalability and efficiency of DeFi platforms, we expect continuous innovation in smart contract development that will be able to form more sophisticated and secure DeFi protocols. The constantly evolving blockchain algorithm is the foundation for eliminating uncertainties and doubts about this technology.</p>



<p>Once regulatory clarity and frameworks for DeFi are formed, the time where DeFi platforms become more integrated into the mainstream financial ecosystem, even extending beyond finance to appear in other sectors like healthcare will be in the not too distant future.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="heading2-2">The Bright Future Is in Our Hands</h2>



<p>Technology moves at an incredibly fast pace. What is popular today may be obsolete in just a few years. What was once thought impossible could become standard in less than a decade.</p>



<p>For this reason, it’s hard to know whether these predictions will come true. But it’ll be interesting to see how these ideas manifest in the years to come. Regardless of the technology scenario in 50 years, we believe that the rapid changes and developments of technological advancements are all aimed at a single ultimate goal: improving human existence and making the digital and physical worlds better.</p>



<p>It is worth noting that perfection is a far-reaching concept at all times. It cannot be denied that the future promises many positive outcomes. However, existing alongside new opportunities is a potential challenge. As humans willingly trade discretion in increasingly ubiquitous digital systems for improved quality of life, personal privacy has the potential to become a distant memory.</p>



<p>In the era of internet-enabled technology, indirect interaction through social networking platforms and communication tools unintentionally creates many security holes. If you do not nurture and maintain unmediated human relationships but rely on mostly unregulated internet, plus commercial impetus remains dominant, and international regulation remains weak, people giving away their data for convenience access has the potential to cause dangerous disruptions across society.</p>



<p>For the time being, what we can do is monitor the development of technology, watch the market trends, and listen to the experts who are involved in their development to protect personal information and minimize cybersecurity attacks.</p>



<p>You don’t have to be a scientist to contribute to a bright picture of our future’s physical and digital worlds. Instead, integrating the latest technologies in software projects is a viable way to create value across various industries and domains. What changes do you anticipate in the digital world’s platform companies? If you have an innovative business idea that cannot wait to be put into action, connect with our experts at Orient Software and learn how we can help.</p><p>The post <a href="/the-future-of-technology-in-50-years-to-come/">The Future of Technology in 50 Years to Come</a> first appeared on <a href="">Seabed2crest</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/the-future-of-technology-in-50-years-to-come/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
